<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE xliff PUBLIC "-//XLIFF//DTD XLIFF//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/committees/xliff/documents/xliff.dtd">
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file source-language="en" target-language="hu" datatype="plaintext" original="messages" date="2017-08-25T18:50:40Z" product-name="messages">
    <header/>
    <body>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Untitled</source>
        <target>Cím nélkül</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="2">
        <source>Administrative / Biographical history</source>
        <target>Adminisztratív / életrajzi történet</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="3">
        <source>Administrative history</source>
        <target>Szervtörténet</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="4">
        <source>Biographical history</source>
        <target>Életrajz</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="5">
        <source>This archival description, or one of its higher levels, %1%requires%2% at least one %3%creator%4%.</source>
        <target>Ehhez a levéltári leíráshoz, vagy egyik magasabb szintjéhez, legalább egy %3%iratképző%4% %1%szükséges%2%.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="6">
        <source>%1%Date(s)%2% - are not consistent with %3%higher levels%2%.</source>
        <target>%1%Dátum(ok)%2% nem egyeznek a %3%magasabb szintekkel%4%.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="7">
        <source>%1%Date(s)%2% - This is a %3%mandatory%4% element.</source>
        <target>%1%dátum(ok)%2% – Az elem kitöltése %3%kötelező%4%.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="8">
        <source>%1%Extent and medium%2% - This is a %3%mandatory%4% element.</source>
        <target>%1% Méret és adathordozó %2% - Az elem kitöltése  %3% kötelező %4%</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="9">
        <source>%1%Identifier%2% - This is a %3%mandatory%4% element.</source>
        <target>%1% Azonosító %2% - Az elem kitöltése  %3% kötelező %4%</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="10">
        <source>%1%Level of description%2% - Value "%value%" is not consistent with higher levels.</source>
        <target>%1%Leírási szint%2% – Érték %3%érték%4% nem egyezik a magasabb szintekkel.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="11">
        <source>%1%Level of description%2% - This is a %3%mandatory%4% element.</source>
        <target>%1%Leírási szint(ek)%2% – Ez egy %3%kötelező%4% elem.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="12">
        <source>%1%Title%2% - This is a %3%mandatory%4% element.</source>
        <target>%1%Cím%2% - Az elem megadása %3%kötelező%4%.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="13">
        <source>Add new archival description</source>
        <target>Új levéltári leírás hozzáadása</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="14">
        <source>Edit %1%</source>
        <target>%1% szerkesztése</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="15">
        <source>File list</source>
        <target>Fájllista</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="16">
        <source>Reference code</source>
        <target>Jelzet</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="17">
        <source>Title</source>
        <target>Cím</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="18">
        <source>Date(s)</source>
        <target>Dátum(ok)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="19">
        <source>Conditions governing access</source>
        <target>Jogi helyzet</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="20">
        <source>This is a duplicate of record %1%</source>
        <target>Ez a következő irat másolata: %1%</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="21">
        <source>Identity area</source>
        <target>Azonosítási adatcsoport</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="22">
        <source>Provide a specific local reference code, control number, or other unique identifier. The country and repository code will be automatically added from the linked repository record to form a full reference code. (ISAD 3.1.1)</source>
        <target>Adjuk meg egy egyéni helyi referencia kódot, kontrollszámot, vagy más egyedi azonosítót. Az ország és a levéltár kódja a csatolt levéltári rekordból automatikusan hozzá lesz adva a teljes referencia kód kialakításához. (ISAD 3.1.1)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="23">
        <source>Identifier</source>
        <target>Jelzet</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="24">
        <source>This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target>Az elem megadása kötelező.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="25">
        <source>Provide either a formal title or a concise supplied title in accordance with the rules of multilevel description and national conventions. (ISAD 3.1.2)</source>
        <target>Adjuk meg a többszintű leírás szabályainak és a nemzeti szabványoknak megfelelő eredeti címet, vagy egy általunk megállapított, tömör címet. (ISAD 3.1.2)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="26">
        <source>"Identify and record the date(s) of the unit of description. Identify the type of date given. Record as a single date or a range of dates as appropriate.” (ISAD 3.1.3). The Date display field can be used to enter free-text date information, including typographical marks to express approximation, uncertainty, or qualification. Use the start and end fields to make the dates searchable. Do not use any qualifiers or typographical symbols to express uncertainty. Acceptable date formats: YYYYMMDD, YYYY-MM-DD, YYYY-MM, YYYY.</source>
        <target>„A leírási egység dátumának (időkörének) meghatározása. Tüntessük fel a megadott dátum típusát. Megadható egyetlen időpont, és időintervallum is.” (ISAD 3.1.3)  A &lt;strong&gt;Dátum&lt;/strong&gt; ablakmező felhasználható szabad-szövegű dátum bevitelére, beleértve olyan tipográfiai jeleket is amelyek hozzávetőlegességet, bizonytalanságot vagy minősítést fejeznek ki. A dátumok kereshetővé tételéhez használja a &lt;strong&gt;Kezdő dátum&lt;/strong&gt; és &lt;/strong&gt;Befejező dátum&lt;/strong&gt; mezőket. Itt ne használjon olyan minősítőket és tipográfiai szimbólumokat amelyek bizonytalanságot fejeznek ki. Elfogadható dátum formátumok: ÉÉÉÉHHNN, ÉÉÉÉ-HH-NN, ÉÉÉÉ-HH, ÉÉÉÉ.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="27">
        <source>Record the level of this unit of description. (ISAD 3.1.4)</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük a leírási egység szintjét. (ISAD 3.1.4)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="28">
        <source>Level of description</source>
        <target>Leírási szint</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="29">
        <source>Identifier: Provide a specific local reference code, control number, or other unique identifier. Level of description: Record the level of this unit of description. Title: Provide either a formal title or a concise supplied title in accordance with the rules of multilevel description and national conventions.</source>
        <target>Azonosító: Határozzon meg egy speciális helyi vonatkozó kódot, ellenőrzési számot, vagy egyéb egyedi azonosítót. A leírás szintje: Rögzítse a leírási egység szintjét. Cím: Határozzon meg vagy egy külsőleges címet, vagy egy tömörre kialakított címet a többszintes leírások szabályaival és a nemzeti szabálykörnyezettel megegyezően.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="30">
        <source>Record the extent of the unit of description by giving the number of physical or logical units in arabic numerals and the unit of measurement. Give the specific medium (media) of the unit of description. Separate multiple extents with a linebreak. (ISAD 3.1.5)</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük a leírási egység terjedelmét a fizikai vagy logikai egységek mennyiségének arab számokkal, és a mértékegységgel történő megadásával. Nevezzük meg az anyagban található specifikus adathordozókat. A többféle terjedelmi adatot sortöréssel válasszuk el egymástól (ISAD 3.1.5)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="31">
        <source>Extent and medium</source>
        <target>Terjedelem, adathordozók</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="32">
        <source>Context area</source>
        <target>Kontextusra vonatkozó adatcsoport</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="33">
        <source>Name of creator(s)</source>
        <target>Iratképző(k) neve</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="34">
        <source>This archival description, or one of its higher levels, requires at least one creator.</source>
        <target>Ehhez a levéltári leíráshoz, vagy egyik magasabb szintjéhez, legalább egy iratképző szükséges.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="35">
        <source>Record the name of the organization(s) or the individual(s) responsible for the creation, accumulation and maintenance of the records in the unit of description. Search for an existing name in the authority records by typing the first few characters of the name. Alternatively, type a new name to create and link to a new authority record. (ISAD 3.2.1)</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük a leírási egységet létrehozó vagy azt felhalmozó és megőrző  személyeket, szervezeteket. Az első pár karakter begépelésével kereshet a létező azonosító leírások közt, vagy új név beírásával új azonosító leírást hozhat létre. (ISAD 3.2.1)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="36">
        <source>Record the name of the organization which has custody of the archival material. Search for an existing name in the archival institution records by typing the first few characters of the name. Alternatively, type a new name to create and link to a new archival institution record.</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük a levéltári anyagot őrző szervezet nevét. Az első pár karakter begépelésével kereshet a létező intézmények közt, vagy új név beírásával új levéltári intézményt hozhat létre.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="37">
        <source>Record the successive transfers of ownership, responsibility and/or custody of the unit of description and indicate those actions, such as history of the arrangement, production of contemporary finding aids, re-use of the records for other purposes or software migrations, that have contributed to its present structure and arrangement. Give the dates of these actions, insofar as they can be ascertained. If the archival history is unknown, record that information. (ISAD 3.2.3)</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük a leírási egységet érintő tulajdoni változásokat, a megőrzésért és kezelésért felelős személyek/szervezetek változásait, valamint mindazokat a mozzanatokat, így a rendezési, segédletkészítési munkálatokat, migrálásokat, a levéltári anyag más célú felhasználását, amelyek kihatottak a leírási egység mai állapotára és rendezettségére. Ahol lehet, mindig adjunk meg dátumokat, amennyiben megállapíthatóak. Azt is tüntessük fel, ha a megőrzés történetéről nem maradtak fenn adatok. (ISAD 3.2.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="38">
        <source>Record the source from which the unit of description was acquired and the date and/or method of acquisition if any or all of this information is not confidential. If the source is unknown, record that information. Optionally, add accession numbers or codes. (ISAD 3.2.4)</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük a forrást, ahonnan a leírási egység a levéltárba került, valamint a gyarapodás dátumát és módját is, amennyiben ezek az információk nem bizalmasak. Ha a forrás ismeretlen, ezt tüntessük fel. Opcionálisan a gyarapodási számot, kódot is rögzíthetjük. (ISAD 3.2.4)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="39">
        <source>Immediate source of acquisition or transfer</source>
        <target>Levéltárba kerülés/Gyarapodás</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="40">
        <source>Content and structure area</source>
        <target>A tartalomra és a szerkezetre vonatkozóadatcsoport</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="41">
        <source>Give a summary of the scope (such as, time periods, geography) and content, (such as documentary forms, subject matter, administrative processes) of the unit of description, appropriate to the level of description. (ISAD 3.3.1)</source>
        <target>Foglalja össze a leírási egység tárgyát (például korszakok, földrajzi területrk szerint) és tartalmát (például irattípusok, tárgykörök, hivatali eljárások szerint), a leírás szintjének megfelelően. (ISAD 3.3.1)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="42">
        <source>Record appraisal, destruction and scheduling actions taken on or planned for the unit of description, especially if they may affect the interpretation of the material. (ISAD 3.3.2)</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük a leírási egységen végrehajtott vagy tervezett iratértékelési, selejtezési munkálatokat, különösen, ha azok befolyásolhatják az anyag értelmezését. (ISAD 3.3.2)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="43">
        <source>Appraisal, destruction and scheduling</source>
        <target>Iratértékelés, selejtezés, tervezés </target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="44">
        <source>Indicate if accruals are expected. Where appropriate, give an estimate of their quantity and frequency. (ISAD 3.3.3)</source>
        <target>Jelölje meg azt, hogy ha bővülés várható. Ahol lehetséges, adja meg a hozzávetőleges mennyiséget és gyakoriságot. (ISAD 3.3.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="45">
        <source>Specify the internal structure, order and/or the system of classification of the unit of description. Note how these have been treated by the archivist. For electronic records, record or reference information on system design. (ISAD 3.3.4)</source>
        <target>Ismertessük a leírási egység belső szerkezetét, rendezettségét, és/vagy osztályozásának rendszerét. Jelezzük, hogy a levéltáros milyen rendezési munkákat végzett az iraton. Elektronikus iratoknál adjuk meg vagy hivatkozzuk a rendszertervre vonatkozó információkat. (ISAD 3.3.4)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="46">
        <source>System of arrangement</source>
        <target>Leírási egység szerkezete</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="47">
        <source>Conditions of access and use area</source>
        <target>A hozzáférésre és használatra vonatkozó adatcsoport</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="48">
        <source>Specify the law or legal status, contract, regulation or policy that affects access to the unit of description. Indicate the extent of the period of closure and the date at which the material will open when appropriate. (ISAD 3.4.1)</source>
        <target>Ismertessük a törvényeket, a jogi helyzetet, valamint mindazon szerződéseket, előírásokat és irányelveket, amelyek befolyásolják a hozzáférést a leírási egységhez. Ha lehetséges, zárolt anyagnál tüntessük fel, mennyi ideig tart a zárolás és hogy mikor lesz feloldva. (ISAD 3.4.1)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="49">
        <source>Give information about conditions, such as copyright, governing the reproduction of the unit of description after access has been provided. If the existence of such conditions is unknown, record this. If there are no conditions, no statement is necessary. (ISAD 3.4.2)</source>
        <target>Adjon információt a leírási egység másolhatóságát szabályozó föltételekről, mint például a szerzői jog. Tüntesse föl azt is, ha a másolási föltételekről nincs információ. Ha nincsenek korlátozások, azt nem kell külön feltüntetni. (ISAD 3.4.2)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="50">
        <source>Conditions governing reproduction</source>
        <target>Reprodukciós korlátozások </target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="51">
        <source>Record the language(s) of the materials comprising the unit of description. (ISAD 3.4.3)</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük a leírási egységet alkotó anyagok nyelvét (ISAD 3.4.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="52">
        <source>Language of material</source>
        <target>Nyelv</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="53">
        <source>Record the script(s) of the materials comprising the unit of description. (ISAD 3.4.3)</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük a leírási egységet alkotó anyagok írásrendszerét. (ISAD 3.4.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="54">
        <source>Script of material</source>
        <target>Anyag írásrendszere</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="55">
        <source>Note any distinctive alphabets, scripts, symbol systems or abbreviations employed. (ISAD 3.4.3)</source>
        <target>Adja meg a használt ábécéket, írásrendszereket, jelrendszereket vagy rövidítéseket.  (ISAD 3.4.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="56">
        <source>Language and script notes</source>
        <target>Nyelv és írásrendszer megjegyzések</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="57">
        <source>Indicate any important physical conditions, such as preservation requirements, that affect the use of the unit of description. Note any software and/or hardware required to access the unit of description.</source>
        <target>Jelöljön meg bármilyen fizikai állapotot, mint például olyan megőrzési elvárásokat, amelyek befolyásolják a leírási egység használatát. Jelöljön meg minden olyan szoftver és/vagy hardver előfeltételt, amely szükséges a leírási egység eléréséhez.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="58">
        <source>Physical characteristics and technical requirements</source>
        <target>Fizikai jellemzők, technikai követelmények</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="59">
        <source>Give information about any finding aids that the repository or records creator may have that provide information relating to the context and contents of the unit of description. If appropriate, include information on where to obtain a copy. (ISAD 3.4.5)</source>
        <target>Nyújtsunk információkat az iratépző, illetve a levéltár átlal létrehozott segédletekről, amelyek a leírási egység kontextusáról és tartalmáról tájékoztatnak. Ha lehetséges, azt is tüntessük fel, hol és hogyan érhetők el. (ISAD 3.4.5)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="60">
        <source>Allied materials area</source>
        <target>Kapcsolódó anyagokra vonatkozó adatcsoport</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="61">
        <source>If the original of the unit of description is available (either in the institution or elsewhere) record its location, together with any significant control numbers. If the originals no longer exist, or their location is unknown, give that information. (ISAD 3.5.1)</source>
        <target>Ha a leírási egység eredeti példányai elérhetőek (az intézményben vagy bárhol máshol), rögzítse a helyüket, bármilyen jelentős ellenőrzési számmal együtt. Ha az eredeti példányok megsemmisültek, vagy fellelhetőségi helyük ismeretlen, adja meg ezeket az információkat. (ISAD 3.5.1)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="62">
        <source>Existence and location of originals</source>
        <target>Eredeti példányok léte és őrzőhelye</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="63">
        <source>If the copy of the unit of description is available (either in the institution or elsewhere) record its location, together with any significant control numbers. (ISAD 3.5.2)</source>
        <target>Ha a leírási egység másolata elérhető (az intézményben vagy bárhol máshol) rögzítse a helyét, bármilyen jelentős ellenőrzési számmal együtt. (ISAD 3.5.2)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="64">
        <source>Existence and location of copies</source>
        <target>Másolatok léte és őrzőhelye </target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="65">
        <source>Record information about units of description in the same repository or elsewhere that are related by provenance or other association(s). Use appropriate introductory wording and explain the nature of the relationship . If the related unit of description is a finding aid, use the finding aids element of description (3.4.5) to make the reference to it. (ISAD 3.5.3)</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük az ugyanazon vagy más intézményben őrzött leírási egységekről szóló információkat, melyek provenienciájuk vagy egyéb jellemzőjük révén összefüggenek a leírási egységgel. Fejtsük ki a kapcsolat természetét. Ha a kapcsolódó leírási egység segédlet, akkor a segédletek (3.4.5) között hivatkozzunk rá. (ISAD 3.5.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="66">
        <source>Related units of description</source>
        <target>Kapcsolódó leírási egységek </target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="67">
        <source>Related descriptions</source>
        <target>Kapcsolódó leírások</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="68">
        <source>To create a relationship between this description and another description held in AtoM, begin typing the name of the related description and select it from the autocomplete drop-down menu when it appears below. Multiple relationships can be created.</source>
        <target>Kapcsolat létrehozásához ezen leírás és egy másik, AtoMban tárolt leírás között kezdje el a kapcsolódó leírás címét gépelni, majd az automatikusan legördülő menüből válassza ki. Többszörös kapcsolat is létrehozható.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="69">
        <source>Notes area</source>
        <target>Megjegyzések adatcsoport</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="70">
        <source>Access points</source>
        <target>Kapcsolódási pontok</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="71">
        <source>Subject access points</source>
        <target>Téma kapcsolódási pontok</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="72">
        <source>Place access points</source>
        <target>Hely kapcsolódási pontok</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="73">
        <source>Name access points (subjects)</source>
        <target>Név kapcsolódási pontok (tárgyak)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="74">
        <source>Description control area</source>
        <target>Ellenőrző adatcsoport</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="75">
        <source>Record a unique description identifier in accordance with local and/or national conventions. If the description is to be used internationally, record the code of the country in which the description was created in accordance with the latest version of ISO 3166 - Codes for the representation of names of countries. Where the creator of the description is an international organisation, give the organisational identifier in place of the country code.</source>
        <target>Rögzítsünk egy helyi és/vagy nemzeti szabványoknak megfelelő egyedi leírás azonosítót. Ha a leírást nemzetközi használatra készül, akkor a készítő ország ISO 3166 legfrissebb változata szerinti országnév-kódot is jegyezzük fel. Ahol a leírás készítője nemzetközi szervezet, ott az ország kódja helyett a szervezeti azonosítót adjuk meg.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="76">
        <source>Description identifier</source>
        <target>Leírási azonosító</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="77">
        <source>Record the full authorised form of name(s) of the agency(ies) responsible for creating, modifying or disseminating the description or, alternatively, record a code for the agency in accordance with the national or international agency code standard.</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük a leírás létrehozásáért, módosításáért vagy terjesztéséért felelős intézmény(ek) teljes kitüntetett névalakját, vagy nemzeti vagy nemzetközi kódolási szabványoknak megfelelő intézményi kódját.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="78">
        <source>Institution identifier</source>
        <target>Intézmény azonosítója</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="79">
        <source>Record the international, national and/or local rules or conventions followed in preparing the description. (ISAD 3.7.2)</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük az összes, a leírás elkészítése során felhasznált nemzetközi, nemzeti vagy helyi szabványt, szabályozást, utasítást és mintát. (ISAD 3.7.2)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="80">
        <source>Rules or conventions</source>
        <target>Szabványok és szabályok</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="81">
        <source>Status</source>
        <target>Állapot</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="82">
        <source>Record the current status of the description, indicating whether it is a draft, finalized and/or revised or deleted.</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük a leírás aktuális státuszát, miszerint vázlat, végleges és/vagy felülvizsgált, vagy törölt.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="83">
        <source>Record whether the description consists of a minimal, partial or full level of detail in accordance with relevant international and/or national guidelines and/or rules.</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük, hogy a leírás részletességi szintje minimális, részleges, vagy teljes a vonatkozó nemzetközi és/vagy nemzeti irányelvek és/vagy szabályok szerint.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="84">
        <source>Level of detail</source>
        <target>A leírás részletezettségi szintje</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="85">
        <source>Record the date(s) the entry was prepared and/or revised.</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük a bejegyzés készítésének és/vagy felülvizsgálatának dátumát.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="86">
        <source>Dates of creation, revision and deletion</source>
        <target>A leírás készítésének, felülvizsgálatának és törlésének ideje</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="87">
        <source>Indicate the language(s) used to create the description of the archival material.</source>
        <target>Jelölje meg a levéltári anyag leírásához használt nyelvet(nyelveket).</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="88">
        <source>Language(s)</source>
        <target>Nyelv(ek)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="89">
        <source>Indicate the script(s) used to create the description of the archival material.</source>
        <target>Jelölje meg a levéltári anyag leírásához használt írásrendszert(írásrendszereket).</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="90">
        <source>Script(s)</source>
        <target>Írásrendszer(ek)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="91">
        <source>Record citations for any external sources used in the archival description (such as the Scope and Content, Archival History, or Notes fields).</source>
        <target>Rögzítsük a levéltári leírás készítése során (például a Tárgy és Tartalom, A Megőrzés Története, és Megjegyzések mezőkben) felhasznált külső forrásokra mutató hivatkozásokat.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="92">
        <source>Sources</source>
        <target>Források</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="93">
        <source>Edit identity area</source>
        <target>Azonosítási adatcsoport szerkesztése</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="94">
        <source>Edit context area</source>
        <target>Kontextusra vonatkozó adatcsoport szerkesztése</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="95">
        <source>Related function</source>
        <target>Kapcsolódó funkció</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="96">
        <source>Repository</source>
        <target>Levéltár</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="97">
        <source>Archival history</source>
        <target>A megőrzés története</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="98">
        <source>Edit content and structure area</source>
        <target>Tartalom és struktúra adatcsoport szerkesztése</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="99">
        <source>Scope and content</source>
        <target>Tárgy és tartalom</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="100">
        <source>Accruals</source>
        <target>Jövőbeni gyarapodás</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="101">
        <source>Edit conditions of access and use area</source>
        <target>A hozzáférésre és használatra vonatkozó adatcsoport</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="102">
        <source>Finding aids</source>
        <target>Segédletek</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="103">
        <source>Edit alied materials area</source>
        <target>Kapcsolódó anyagokra vonatkozó adatcsoport szerkesztése</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="104">
        <source>Publication note</source>
        <target>Publikációk</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="105">
        <source>Edit notes area</source>
        <target>Megjegyzések adatcsoport szerkesztése</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="106">
        <source>Note</source>
        <target>Megjegyzés</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="107">
        <source>Edit access points</source>
        <target>Hozzáférési pontok szerkesztése</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="108">
        <source>Edit description control area</source>
        <target>Ellenőrző adatcsoport szerkesztése</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="109">
        <source>Rules and/or conventions used</source>
        <target>Felhasznált szabályok és/vagy előírások</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="110">
        <source>Dates of creation revision deletion</source>
        <target>A leírás készítésének felülvizsgálatának törlésének ideje</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="111">
        <source>Archivist's note</source>
        <target>A leírás készítése és készítője</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="112">
        <source>Rights area</source>
        <target>Jogi státusz adatcsoport</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="113">
        <source>Accession area</source>
        <target>Gyarapodási adatcsoport</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="114">
        <source>Type</source>
        <target>Típus</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="115">
        <source>Date</source>
        <target>Dátum</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="116">
        <source>Start</source>
        <target>Kezdet</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="117">
        <source>End</source>
        <target>Befejező dátum</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="118">
        <source>Genre access points</source>
        <target>Műfaji Kapcsolódási pontok</target>
      </trans-unit>
    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>
