<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE xliff PUBLIC "-//XLIFF//DTD XLIFF//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/committees/xliff/documents/xliff.dtd">
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file source-language="en" target-language="nb" datatype="plaintext" original="messages" date="2017-08-25T18:54:37Z" product-name="messages">
    <header/>
    <body>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Untitled</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="2">
        <source>Administrative / Biographical history</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="3">
        <source>Administrative history</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="4">
        <source>Biographical history</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="5">
        <source>Identifier - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="6">
        <source>Name and location of repository - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="7">
        <source>Title - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="8">
        <source>Date(s) - are not consistent with higher levels.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="9">
        <source>Date(s) - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="10">
        <source>Extent - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="11">
        <source>This archival description, or one of its higher levels, requires at least one creator.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="12">
        <source>Scope and content - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="13">
        <source>Add new archival description</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="14">
        <source>Edit %1%</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="15">
        <source>This is a duplicate of record %1%</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="16">
        <source>Identity elements</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="17">
        <source>At the highest level of a multilevel description or in a single level description, provide a unique identifier for the materials being described in accordance with the institution’s administrative control system. Optionally, devise unique identifiers at lower levels of a multilevel description. (DACS 2.1.3) The country and repository code will be automatically added from the linked repository record to form a full reference code.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="18">
        <source>Identifier</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="19">
        <source>This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="20">
        <source>Name and location of repository</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="21">
        <source>Explicitly state the name of the repository, including any parent bodies (DACS 2.2.2). Search for an existing name in the archival institution records by typing the first few characters of the name. Alternatively, type a new name to create and link to a new archival institution record.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="22">
        <source>Select a level of description from the drop-down menu. Follow any relevant local or institutional guidelines in selecting the proper level of description. See DACS (2013) Chapter 1 for further guidance.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="23">
        <source>Levels of description</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="24">
        <source>In the absence of a meaningful formal title, compose a brief title that uniquely identifies the material, normally consisting of a name segment, a term indicating the nature of the unit being described, and optionally a topical segment. Do not enclose devised titles in square brackets. (DACS 2.3.3)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="25">
        <source>Title</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="26">
        <source>Record dates of creation, record-keeping activity, publication, or broadcast as appropriate to the materials being described. (DACS 2.4.3) The Date display field can be used to enter free-text date information, including typographical marks to express approximation, uncertainty, or qualification. Use the start and end fields to make the dates searchable. Do not use any qualifiers or typographical symbols. Acceptable date formats: YYYYMMDD, YYYY-MM-DD, YYYY-MM, YYYY.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="27">
        <source>Record the quantity of the material in terms of its physical extent as linear or cubic feet, number of items, or number of containers or carriers. (DACS 2.5.4). Optionally, record the quantity in terms of material type(s) (DACS 2.5.5), and/or qualify the statement of physical extent to hightlight the existence of material types that re important (DACS 2.5.6).</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="28">
        <source>Extent</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="29">
        <source>Name of creator(s)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="30">
        <source>Record the name(s) of the creator(s) identified in the name element in the devised title of the materials using standardized vocabularies or with rules for formulating standardized names (DACS 2.6.4). Search for an existing name in the authority records by typing the first few characters of the name. Alternatively, type a new name to create and link to a new authority record.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="31">
        <source>&lt;strong&gt;Identifier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Provide a unique identifier for the materials being described in accordance with the institution’s administrative control system.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level of description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Record the level of this unit of description.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the absence of a meaningful formal title, compose a brief title that uniquely identifies the material.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Record a date of creation.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="32">
        <source>Content and structure elements</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="33">
        <source>Record information about the nature of the materials and activities reflected in the unit being described to enable users to judge its potential relevance, including information about functions, activities, transations, and processes; documentary form(s) or intellectual characteristics; content dates; geographic areas and places; subject matter; completeness of the materials; or any other information that assists the user in evaluating the relevance of the materials. (DACS 3.1)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="34">
        <source>Scope and content</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="35">
        <source>Describe the current arrangement of the material in terms of the various aggregations within it and their relationships. (DACS 3.2.3)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="36">
        <source>System of arrangement</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="37">
        <source>Conditions of access and use elements</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="38">
        <source>Give information about any restrictions on access to the unit being described (or parts thereof) as a result of the nature of the information therein or statutory/contractual requirements. As appropriate, specify the details of the restriction. If there are no restrictions, state that fact. (DACS 4.1.5)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="39">
        <source>Conditions governing access</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="40">
        <source>Provide information about the physical characteristics or condition of the unit being described that limit access to it or restrict its use. (DACS 4.2.5)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="41">
        <source>Physical access</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="42">
        <source>Provide information about any special equipment required to view or access the unit being described, if it is not clear from the Extent element. (DACS 4.3.5)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="43">
        <source>Technical access</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="44">
        <source>Give information about copyright status and any other conditions governing the reproduction, publication, and further use (e.g., display, public screening, broadcast, etc.) of the unit being described after access has been provided. (DACS 4.4.5)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="45">
        <source>Conditions governing reproduction and use</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="46">
        <source>Record the language(s) of the materials being described. (DACS 4.5.2)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="47">
        <source>Languages of the material</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="48">
        <source>Record the scripts(s) of the materials being described.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="49">
        <source>Scripts of the material</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="50">
        <source>Record information about any distinctive alphabets, scripts, symbol systems, or abbreviations employed (DACS 4.5.3). If there is no language content, record “no linguistic content.” (DACS 4.5.4)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="51">
        <source>Language and script notes</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="52">
        <source>Record information about any existing finding aids that provide information relating to the context and contents of the unit being described... including any relevant information about its location or availability, and any other information necessary to assist the user in evaluating its usefulness. Include finding aids prepared by the creator (e.g., registers, indexes, etc.) that are part of the unit being described. (DACS 4.6.2)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="53">
        <source>Acquisition and appraisal elements</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="54">
        <source>Custodial history</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="55">
        <source>Record the successive transfers of ownership, responsibility, or custody or control of the unit being described from the time it left the possession of the creator until its acquisition by the repository, along with the dates thereof, insofar as this information can be ascertained and is significant to the user’s understanding of the authenticity. (DACS 5.1.3)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="56">
        <source>Record the source(s) from which the materials being described were acquired, the date(s) of acquisition, and the method of acquisition, if this information is not confidential. (DACS 5.2.3)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="57">
        <source>Immediate source of acquisition or transfer</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="58">
        <source>Where the destruction or retention of archival materials has a bearing on the interpretation and use of the unit being described, provide information about the materials destroyed or retained and provide the reason(s) for the appraisal decision(s), where known. (DACS 5.3.4)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="59">
        <source>Appraisal, destruction and scheduling information</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="60">
        <source>If known, indicate whether or not further accruals are expected. When appropriate, indicate frequency and volume. (DACS 5.4.2)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="61">
        <source>Related materials elements</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="62">
        <source>If the materials being described are reproductions and the originals are located elsewhere, give the location of the originals (DACS 6.1.4). Record any identifying numbers that may help in locating the originals in the cited location (DACS 6.1.6).</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="63">
        <source>Existence and location of originals</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="64">
        <source>If a copy of all or part of the material being described is available, in addition to the originals, record information about the medium and location of the copy, any identifying numbers, and any conditions on the use or availability of the copy. If a copy of only a part of the unit being described is available, indicate which part. If the materials being described are available via remote access (electronically or otherwise), provide the relevant information needed to access them. (DACS 6.2.3)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="65">
        <source>Existence and location of copies</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="66">
        <source>If there are materials that have a direct and significant connection to those being described by reason of closely shared responsibility or sphere of activity, provide the title, location, and, optionally, the reference number(s) of the related materials and their relationship with the materials being described. (DACS 6.3.5)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="67">
        <source>Related archival materials</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="68">
        <source>Related descriptions</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="69">
        <source>To create a relationship between this description and another description held in AtoM, begin typing the name of the related description and select it from the autocomplete drop-down menu when it appears below. Multiple relationships can be created.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="70">
        <source>Notes element</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="71">
        <source>Description control element</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="72">
        <source>Record relevant information about sources consulted in establishing or revising the description. (DACS 8.1.3)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="73">
        <source>Sources used</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="74">
        <source>Record the international, national or local rules or conventions followed in preparing the description. (DACS 8.1.4)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="75">
        <source>Rules or conventions</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="76">
        <source>Access points</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="77">
        <source>Subject access points</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="78">
        <source>Place access points</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="79">
        <source>Genre access points</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="80">
        <source>Name access points (subjects)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="81">
        <source>Edit identity elements</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="82">
        <source>Reference code</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="83">
        <source>Level of description</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="84">
        <source>Date(s)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="85">
        <source>Related function</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="86">
        <source>Edit context and structure elements</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="87">
        <source>Edit conditions of access and use elements</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="88">
        <source>Conditions governing reproduction</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="89">
        <source>Finding aids</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="90">
        <source>Edit acquisition and appraisal elements</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="91">
        <source>Immediate source of acquisition</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="92">
        <source>Accruals</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="93">
        <source>Edit related materials elements</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="94">
        <source>Publication notes</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="95">
        <source>Edit notes element</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="96">
        <source>General note</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="97">
        <source>Specialized notes</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="98">
        <source>Edit description control element</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="99">
        <source>Archivist's note</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="100">
        <source>Edit access points</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="101">
        <source>Rights area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="102">
        <source>Accession area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>
