<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE xliff PUBLIC "-//XLIFF//DTD XLIFF//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/committees/xliff/documents/xliff.dtd">
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file source-language="en" target-language="ko" datatype="plaintext" original="messages" date="2016-04-19T21:27:45Z" product-name="messages">
    <header/>
    <body>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Add new archival description</source>
        <target>기록물 기술정보 추가</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="2">
        <source>Untitled</source>
        <target>제목없음</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="3">
        <source>Edit %1%</source>
        <target>%1% 편집</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="4">
        <source>Identifier - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target>식별자 - 이 항목은 필수 요소입니다. </target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="5">
        <source>Name and location of repository - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target>기록보존소의 이름과 위치 - 필수요소입니다.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="6">
        <source>Title - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target>제목 - 이 항목은 필수 요소입니다. </target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="7">
        <source>Date(s) - are not consistent with higher levels.</source>
        <target>날짜(들) - 상위계층과 일치하지 않습니다.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="8">
        <source>Date(s) - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target>일자(들) - 이것은 </target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="9">
        <source>Extent - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target>규모 - 이 항목은 필수 요소입니다.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="10">
        <source>This archival description, or one of its higher levels, requires at least one creator.</source>
        <target>이 기록물 기술 또는 상위 계층 요소는 적어도 한명의 생산자 정보가 필요합니다.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="11">
        <source>Scope and content - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target>범위와 내용 - 이 항목은 필수 요소입니다.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="12">
        <source>This is a duplicate of record %1%</source>
        <target>중복된 기록입니다.'%1%'</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="13">
        <source>Identity elements</source>
        <target>식별 요소</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="14">
        <source>Reference code</source>
        <target>참조코드</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="16">
        <source>Identifier</source>
        <target>식별자</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="17">
        <source>This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target>이 항목은 필수 요소입니다.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="18">
        <source>Name and location of repository</source>
        <target>기록보존소의 이름과 위치</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="20">
        <source>Levels of description</source>
        <target>기술 계층</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="21">
        <source>Title</source>
        <target>제목</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="23">
        <source>Extent</source>
        <target>규모</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="24">
        <source>Name of creator(s)</source>
        <target>생산자명</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="27">
        <source>Content and structure elements</source>
        <target>내용과 구조 요소</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="28">
        <source>Scope and content</source>
        <target>범위와 내용</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="29">
        <source>System of arrangement</source>
        <target>정리 시스템</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="30">
        <source>Conditions of access and use elements</source>
        <target>열람 및 이용 요소의 조건</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="31">
        <source>Conditions governing access</source>
        <target>접근 조건</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="32">
        <source>Physical access</source>
        <target>물리적 접근</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="33">
        <source>Technical access</source>
        <target>기술적 접근</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="34">
        <source>Conditions governing reproduction and use</source>
        <target>재생산 및 이용 조건</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="35">
        <source>Languages of the material</source>
        <target>자료의 언어</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="36">
        <source>Scripts of the material</source>
        <target>자료의 규약들</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="37">
        <source>Language and script notes</source>
        <target>기록물의 언어 및 규약</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="38">
        <source>Acquisition and appraisal elements</source>
        <target>수집과 평가 요소</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="39">
        <source>Custodial history</source>
        <target>보관 이력</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="40">
        <source>Immediate source of acquisition or transfer</source>
        <target>수집/이관의 직접적 출처
</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="41">
        <source>Appraisal, destruction and scheduling information</source>
        <target>평가, 폐기, 처리일정 정보</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="42">
        <source>Related materials elements</source>
        <target>관련 자료 요소들</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="43">
        <source>Existence and location of originals</source>
        <target>원본 존재와 소장위치</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="44">
        <source>Existence and location of copies</source>
        <target>복사본의 존재와 소장위치</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="45">
        <source>Related archival materials</source>
        <target>관련 기록 자료</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="46">
        <source>Notes element</source>
        <target>주기 요소</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="47">
        <source>Description control element</source>
        <target>기술통제요소</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="48">
        <source>Sources used</source>
        <target>사용된 자료</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="49">
        <source>Rules or conventions</source>
        <target>규칙 혹은 표준규정 </target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="50">
        <source>Access points</source>
        <target>접근점</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="51">
        <source>Subject access points</source>
        <target>주제 접근점</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="52">
        <source>Place access points</source>
        <target>장소 접근점</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="53">
        <source>Name access points (subjects)</source>
        <target>이름 접근점 (주제)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="54">
        <source>Rights area</source>
        <target>권한 영역</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="55">
        <source>Edit identity elements</source>
        <target>식별 요소 편집하기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="56">
        <source>Level of description</source>
        <target>기술 계층</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="57">
        <source>Date(s)</source>
        <target>일자(시기)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="58">
        <source>Related function</source>
        <target>관련 기능</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="59">
        <source>Edit context and structure elements</source>
        <target>맥락과 구조 </target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="60">
        <source>Edit conditions of access and use elements</source>
        <target>열람 및 이용 요소의 조건 편집하기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="61">
        <source>Conditions governing reproduction</source>
        <target>복사조건</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="62">
        <source>Finding aids</source>
        <target>검색도구</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="63">
        <source>Edit acquisition and appraisal elements</source>
        <target>취득과 평가요소 편집하기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="64">
        <source>Immediate source of acquisition</source>
        <target>수집의 직접적 출처</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="65">
        <source>Accruals</source>
        <target>추가 이관</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="66">
        <source>Edit related materials elements</source>
        <target>관련 자료 요소 편집하기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="67">
        <source>Publication notes</source>
        <target>출판주기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="68">
        <source>Edit notes element</source>
        <target>주기 요소 편집하기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="70">
        <source>Edit description control element</source>
        <target>기술 통제 요소 편집하기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="71">
        <source>Archivist's note</source>
        <target>아키비스트 주기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="72">
        <source>Edit access points</source>
        <target>접근점 편집</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="74">
        <source>Accession area</source>
        <target>인수 영역</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="75">
        <source>General note</source>
        <target>일반 주기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="76">
        <source>Specialized notes</source>
        <target>상세 노트</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="77">
        <source>At the highest level of a multilevel description or in a single level description, provide a unique identifier for the materials being described in accordance with the institution’s administrative control system. Optionally, devise unique identifiers at lower levels of a multilevel description. (DACS 2.1.3) The country and repository code will be automatically added from the linked repository record to form a full reference code.</source>
        <target> 다계층 기술 혹은 단일 계층 기술의 최상위 계층에서, 그 기관의 조직/기관 제어 시스템에 따라 기술된 자료들에 부여한 고유 식별자를 기입하시오. 혹은로, 다계층 기술의 하위 계층에서 고유 식별자들을 고안하라. (DACS 2.1.3) 국가와 기록보존소 코드는 링크된 기록보존소 기록으로부터 전체 참조 코드로 자동적으로 추가될 것입니다.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="78">
        <source>Explicitly state the name of the repository, including any parent bodies (DACS 2.2.2). Search for an existing name in the archival institution records by typing the first few characters of the name. Alternatively, type a new name to create and link to a new archival institution record.</source>
        <target>모 기관 명을 포함하여,  명확한 보관 기관명을 기입하시오 (DACS 2.2.2). 이름의 첫 몇글자를 입력하여 보관 기관의 이름을 찾으시오. 그렇지 않으면, 새로운 기관명을 만들고 이를  새기관명 전거 레커드에 링크시키시오.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="79">
        <source>Select a level of description from the drop-down menu. Follow any relevant local or institutional guidelines in selecting the proper level of description. See DACS (2013) Chapter 1 for further guidance.</source>
        <target>drop-down 메뉴로부터 기술계층을 선택하시오. 기술 계층을 선택할 때는 관련 지역이나 기관에서 사용하는 지침을 따르시오.  이에 대한 추가 정보는 DACS(2013)의 1장을 참고하시오.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="80">
        <source>In the absence of a meaningful formal title, compose a brief title that uniquely identifies the material, normally consisting of a name segment, a term indicating the nature of the unit being described, and optionally a topical segment. Do not enclose devised titles in square brackets. (DACS 2.3.3)</source>
        <target>의미 있는 공식적인 제목이 없을 경우, 대개 이름 세그먼트, 기술된 범위의 성격을 나타내는 용어와 선택적으로 논제 세그먼트로 이루어진 자료를 특별하게 식별한 간결한 주제를 구성해라. 꺾쇠 괄호 안에 창안된 주제를 동봉하지 마라. (DACS 2.3.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="81">
        <source>Record dates of creation, record-keeping activity, publication, or broadcast as appropriate to the materials being described. (DACS 2.4.3) The Date display field can be used to enter free-text date information, including typographical marks to express approximation, uncertainty, or qualification. Use the start and end fields to make the dates searchable. Do not use any qualifiers or typographical symbols. Acceptable date formats: YYYYMMDD, YYYY-MM-DD, YYYY-MM, YYYY.</source>
        <target>기술 단위에 적합하도록 생산 날짜, 기록관리 활동, 출판이나 방송 사항에 대해 기입하시오.(DACS 2.4.3) 날짜 필드에는 대략적이거나 불확실한 기간을 표현할 수 있도록 자 표시를 포함해야 합니다. 시작일과 종료일로 날짜 검색을 가능하도록 만드시오. 어떤 제한자나 특수문자 기호를 사용하면 안됩니다. 받아들일 수 있는 날짜 형식 : YYYYMMDD, YYYY-MM-DD, YYYY-MM, YYYY.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="82">
        <source>Record the quantity of the material in terms of its physical extent as linear or cubic feet, number of items, or number of containers or carriers. (DACS 2.5.4). Optionally, record the quantity in terms of material type(s) (DACS 2.5.5), and/or qualify the statement of physical extent to hightlight the existence of material types that re important (DACS 2.5.6).</source>
        <target>직선이나 큐빅 피트로, 또는 기록물 건 수, 보존 용기나 이동 장치의 수로 수로 기록물의 물리적 수량을 기술하시오. (DACS 2.5.4).  선택적으로 재료의 형태(들)이나 (DACS 2.5.5) 중요하다고 판단되는 재료의 형태를 중심으로 물리적 수량을 기록할 수 있습니다. (DACS 2.5.6).</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="83">
        <source>Record the name(s) of the creator(s) identified in the name element in the devised title of the materials using standardized vocabularies or with rules for formulating standardized names (DACS 2.6.4). Search for an existing name in the authority records by typing the first few characters of the name. Alternatively, type a new name to create and link to a new authority record.</source>
        <target>표준화된 자료집에서 규정된 생산자(들)명이나 표목명에 대한 표준화 규칙을 규정한 자료집의 규칙을 따라 만들어진 생산자(들)명을 기입하시오.(DACS 2.6.4). 이름의 처음 몇 글자를 입력하여 전거레코드에서 존재하는 이름을 찾으시오. 또는, 새로운 이름을 생성하고 새 전거레코드로 링크하시오.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="84">
        <source>&lt;strong&gt;Identifier&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Provide a unique identifier for the materials being described in accordance with the institution’s administrative control system.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level of description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Record the level of this unit of description.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the absence of a meaningful formal title, compose a brief title that uniquely identifies the material.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Record a date of creation.</source>
        <target>&lt;strong&gt;식별자&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;는 기관의 관리 통제 시스템에 따라 기술된 자료에  고유 식별자를 제공합니다.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;기술 단위&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 기록 기술 단위를 기록합니다.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;제목&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;공식 제목이 없을 경우, 기술 단위를 식별할 수 있는  간략한 제목을 부여합니다.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;날짜&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;생산된 날짜를 기록합니다.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="85">
        <source>Record information about the nature of the materials and activities reflected in the unit being described to enable users to judge its potential relevance, including information about functions, activities, transations, and processes; documentary form(s) or intellectual characteristics; content dates; geographic areas and places; subject matter; completeness of the materials; or any other information that assists the user in evaluating the relevance of the materials. (DACS 3.1)</source>
        <target>기능,활동, 번역, 업무, 과정, 문서 형식들 혹은 지적인 특성, 내용 일시, 지리학상의 영역과 장소들, 주제, 자료의 완성도(들), 또는 자료의 타당성을 평가하는데 이용자를 도울 다른 정보를 포함하여 이용자가 잠재적인 타당성을 판단할 수 있도록 기록된 단위에서 반영된 활동과 자료의 속성에 대한 정보를 기록하시오. (DACS 3.1)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="86">
        <source>Describe the current arrangement of the material in terms of the various aggregations within it and their relationships. (DACS 3.2.3)</source>
        <target>다양한 기록물 집합들 사이의 관계를 고려하여 현 기록 정리상태를 기술하시오.(DACS 3.2.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="87">
        <source>Give information about any restrictions on access to the unit being described (or parts thereof) as a result of the nature of the information therein or statutory/contractual requirements. As appropriate, specify the details of the restriction. If there are no restrictions, state that fact. (DACS 4.1.5)</source>
        <target>내부규정이나 법적/계약적 요건에 따라 기술단위에(또는 기술 단위 일부) 적용된 접근 제한 사항에 대해 기입하시오. 가능하다면 제한 사항을 자세히 기술하시오.  만약 사실에 대한 제한사항이 없다면, 없다는 사실을 명시하시오. (DACS 4.1.5)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="88">
        <source>Provide information about the physical characteristics or condition of the unit being described that limit access to it or restrict its use. (DACS 4.2.5)</source>
        <target>접근이 제한되어 있거나 사용이 제한되어 있는 기술하고자 하는 단위의 물리적인 성격이나 조건에 대한 정보를 제공하시오. (DACS 4.2.5)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="89">
        <source>Provide information about any special equipment required to view or access the unit being described, if it is not clear from the Extent element. (DACS 4.3.5)</source>
        <target>기록 규모의 요소에서 명확하지 않은 경우, 기술되는 장치에 접근하거나 보기 위해 필요한 특수 장비에 대한 정보를 제공합니다. (DACS 4.3.5)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="90">
        <source>Give information about copyright status and any other conditions governing the reproduction, publication, and further use (e.g., display, public screening, broadcast, etc.) of the unit being described after access has been provided. (DACS 4.4.5)</source>
        <target>기술 단위의 저작권과  복사, 출판, 이외 기타 용도( 예를 들어, 전시, 방송, 상영)에 적용되는 조건에 관한 정보를 입력하시오. (DACS 4.4.5)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="91">
        <source>Record the language(s) of the materials being described. (DACS 4.5.2)</source>
        <target>기술된 자료의 언어(들)을 기술하시오.(DACS 4.5.2)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="92">
        <source>Record the scripts(s) of the materials being described.</source>
        <target>기술하고자 하는 자료의 규칙(들)을 기록하시오.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="93">
        <source>Record information about any distinctive alphabets, scripts, symbol systems, or abbreviations employed (DACS 4.5.3). If there is no language content, record “no linguistic content.” (DACS 4.5.4)</source>
        <target>특정 알파벳, 규약, 기호체계 또는 약어를 기록하시오(DACS 4.5.3). 언어 콘텐츠가 없다면, "언어 콘텐츠 없음"이라 기록하시오.(DACS 4.5.4)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="94">
        <source>Record information about any existing finding aids that provide information relating to the context and contents of the unit being described... including any relevant information about its location or availability, and any other information necessary to assist the user in evaluating its usefulness. Include finding aids prepared by the creator (e.g., registers, indexes, etc.) that are part of the unit being described. (DACS 4.6.2)</source>
        <target>기술 단위의 내용과 맥락에 대한 정보를 제공하는 검색도구에 대한 정보를 기입하시오...여기에는 자료의 위치나 이용여부에  대한 정보, 또 이용자가 자료의 유용성을 판단할 수 있는 정보를 포함합니다.  기술 단위의 일부분으로 검색 도구(등록장부나 색인 등)가 포함되어 있다면 이를 포함하시오. (DACS 4.6.2) </target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="95">
        <source>Record the successive transfers of ownership, responsibility, or custody or control of the unit being described from the time it left the possession of the creator until its acquisition by the repository, along with the dates thereof, insofar as this information can be ascertained and is significant to the user’s understanding of the authenticity. (DACS 5.1.3)</source>
        <target>생산자로부터 보관소 수집 시점까지 기술 단위의 소유권, 책임 소지, 제어 또는 관리 방식의 변화와 날짜를 꼼꼼히 기록하시오.  이용자가 기록물에 대한 진본성을 이해하는 데 위 사항에 대한 확실한 정보를 가지는 것은 대단히 중요합니다.  (DACS 5.1.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="96">
        <source>Record the source(s) from which the materials being described were acquired, the date(s) of acquisition, and the method of acquisition, if this information is not confidential. (DACS 5.2.3)</source>
        <target>정보가 공개될 수 있다면, 기술 자료의 출처(들), 수집 날짜(들), 방법을 기록하시오. (DACS 5.2.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="97">
        <source>Where the destruction or retention of archival materials has a bearing on the interpretation and use of the unit being described, provide information about the materials destroyed or retained and provide the reason(s) for the appraisal decision(s), where known. (DACS 5.3.4)</source>
        <target>아카이브 자료의 폐기나 처리 일정이 기술 단위의 해석과 사용에 중요한 영향을 끼칠 경우 기록물의 폐기와 보유 상태에 대해 기술하시오. 그리고 공개할 수 있다면, 이러한 평가결정(들)요인(들)대해서도 정보를 제공하시오. (DACS 5.3.4)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="98">
        <source>If known, indicate whether or not further accruals are expected. When appropriate, indicate frequency and volume. (DACS 5.4.2)</source>
        <target>알고 있다면, 향후 추가 이관분이 예상되는지 아닌지를 표시하시오. 적절한 경우, 이의 빈도와 양을 표시하시오. (DACS 5.4.2)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="99">
        <source>If the materials being described are reproductions and the originals are located elsewhere, give the location of the originals (DACS 6.1.4). Record any identifying numbers that may help in locating the originals in the cited location (DACS 6.1.6).</source>
        <target>만약 기술되고 있는 자료가 복제본이고 원본이 다른곳에 위치한다면, 원본의 위치를 제공하시오 (DACS 6.1.4). 인용된 위치에 원본의 위치에 도움을 줄 수 있는 식별 번호가 있다면 이를 기록하시오 (DACS 6.1.6).</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="100">
        <source>If a copy of all or part of the material being described is available, in addition to the originals, record information about the medium and location of the copy, any identifying numbers, and any conditions on the use or availability of the copy. If a copy of only a part of the unit being described is available, indicate which part. If the materials being described are available via remote access (electronically or otherwise), provide the relevant information needed to access them. (DACS 6.2.3)</source>
        <target>기술된 자료의 전체 또는 부분적 복사본이 이용 가능하다면, 원본, 복사본의 매체 및 보관 위치에 대한 기록 정보, 식별번호, 그리고 복사본의 이용 또는 입수 가능한 상태를 추가합니다. 기술된 단위의 유일한 복사본이라면, 그 부분을 표시합니다. 기술된 자료가 원격접근(전자적이든 또는 그렇지 않든)으로 이용가능하다면, 접근 필요에 따라 관계 정보를 제공합니다. (DACS 6.2.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="101">
        <source>If there are materials that have a direct and significant connection to those being described by reason of closely shared responsibility or sphere of activity, provide the title, location, and, optionally, the reference number(s) of the related materials and their relationship with the materials being described. (DACS 6.3.5)</source>
        <target>만약, 자료가 공동의 책임이나 활동 분야에 의해 기록된 사람들에게 직접적이고 중요하게 연결될 경우, 선택적 제목, 위치 등을 제공해 관련 자료 및 자료나 기술 대상과의 관계의 참조 번호(들)을 연결해서 기술할 수 있습니다. (DACS 6.3.5)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="102">
        <source>Related descriptions</source>
        <target>관련 기술</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="103">
        <source>To create a relationship between this description and another description held in AtoM, begin typing the name of the related description and select it from the autocomplete drop-down menu when it appears below. Multiple relationships can be created.</source>
        <target>이 기술과 AtoM의 다른 기술 간의 관계를 설정하려면, 관련 기술명을 몇 자 입력하고 그 아래 나타나는 자동완성 드롭다운 메뉴에서 선택하세요. 2개 이상의 관계 설정이 가능합니다.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="104">
        <source>Record relevant information about sources consulted in establishing or revising the description. (DACS 8.1.3)</source>
        <target>기술하거나 수정하는 과정에서 참고했던 정보원에 대한 관련정보를 기입하시오. (DACS 8.1.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="105">
        <source>Record the international, national or local rules or conventions followed in preparing the description. (DACS 8.1.4)</source>
        <target>기술 작업에서 준수했던 국제적, 국가적 또는 지역적 규칙이나 협약이 있다면 이를 기입합니다. (DACS 8.1.4)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="106">
        <source>Administrative / Biographical history</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="107">
        <source>Administrative history</source>
        <target>행정 연혁</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="108">
        <source>Biographical history</source>
        <target>개인 이력</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="109">
        <source>Genre access points</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>
