<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE xliff PUBLIC "-//XLIFF//DTD XLIFF//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/committees/xliff/documents/xliff.dtd">
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file source-language="EN" target-language="ja" datatype="plaintext" original="messages" date="2017-09-04T11:51:18Z" product-name="messages">
    <header/>
    <body>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Add new archival institution</source>
        <target>新規のアーカイブ機関を追加</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="2">
        <source>Untitled</source>
        <target>無題の</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="3">
        <source>Edit %1%</source>
        <target>編集する %1%</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="4">
        <source>%1%Authorized form of name%2% - This is a %3%mandatory%4% element.</source>
        <target>%1%正式名称%2% - %3%必須項目%4% </target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="5">
        <source>%1%Identifier%2% - This is a %3%mandatory%4% element.</source>
        <target>%1%識別子%2%  - %3%必須項目%4%</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="6">
        <source>%1%Contact information%2% - You %3%must%4% at least include one of the following location or address fields: city, country, postal code, region or street address.</source>
        <target>%1%問い合わせ先%2% - 少なくとも以下の「場所」または「住所」フィールドのひとつを%3%必ず%4%ご記入ください。都市名、国名、郵便番号、区、通り。</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="7">
        <source>%1%Contact information%2% - This is a %3%mandatory%4% element.</source>
        <target>%1%問い合わせ先%2%  - %3%必須項目%4%</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="8">
        <source>Edit %1% - ISDIAH</source>
        <target>編集する %1% - ISDIAH</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="9">
        <source>Identity area</source>
        <target>確認のエリア</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="10">
        <source>"Record the numeric or alpha-numeric code identifying the institution in accordance with the relevant international and national standards." (ISDIAH 5.1.1)</source>
        <target>"国際的・国内的な標準に準じて、機関に付与された数字、またはアルファベットと数字の組み合わせによるコードを記載してください。" (ISDIAH 5.1.1)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="11">
        <source>Identifier</source>
        <target>識別子</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="12">
        <source>This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target>必須項目。</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="13">
        <source>"Record the standardised form of name of the institution, adding appropriate qualifiers (for instance dates, place, etc.), if necessary. Specify separately in the Rules and/or conventions used element (5.6.3) which set of rules has been applied for this element." (ISDIAH 5.1.2)</source>
        <target>"機関の名称を、標準化された形式で記載して下さい。その際、適切な限定詞（例：日付、場所など）を必要なら付記して下さい。それとは別に、記述要素「使用した規則等」（5.6.3）には、この要素の記述にどんな規則を適用したかを記載して下さい。" (ISDIAH 5.1.2)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="14">
        <source>Authorized form of name</source>
        <target>正式名称</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="15">
        <source>This is a mandatory element</source>
        <target>必須項目</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="16">
        <source>"Purpose: To indicate the various forms in which the authorised form of name of an institution occurs in other languages or script form(s). Rule: Record the parallel form(s) of name of the institution in accordance with any relevant national or international conventions or rules applied by the agency that created the description, including any necessary sub elements and/or qualifiers required by those conventions or rules. Specify in the Rules and/or conventions used element (5.6.3) which rules have been applied." (ISDIAH 5.1.3)</source>
        <target>目的：ある機関について、正式名称の、外国語や異なる文字による表記を示すこと。記述規則：記述作成機関が使用する国内・国際規則等に準じた、機関名称の異なる表記を記載して下さい。その場合、適用した規則が要求するサブエレメントや限定詞があればそれも記載して下さい。記述要素「使用した規則等」（5.6.3)で、使用した規則を特定して下さい。" (ISDIAH 5.1.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="17">
        <source>"Record any other name(s) by which the institution may be known. This could include other forms of the same name, acronyms, other institutional names, or changes of name over time, including, if possible, relevant dates." (ISDIAH 5.1.4)</source>
        <target>"機関について、他に知られている名称（複数可）があれば記載してください。ここには、同じ名称の異なる形式での表示、頭字、その他の組織的名称、名称の変遷なども含みます。可能であれば関連する日付も記載してください。" (ISDIAH 5.1.4)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="18">
        <source>Record the type of the institution. (ISDIAH 5.1.5) Select as many types as desired from the drop-down menu; these values are drawn from the Repository Types taxonomy.</source>
        <target>組織の種別を記録する。(ISDIAH 5.1.5)ドロップダウンメニューから望ましい種別を選択する。：この数値は保存機関分類から選ばれる。</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="19">
        <source>Contact area</source>
        <target>連絡のエリア</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="35">
        <source>See ISDIAH 5.2 for contact area information and examples.</source>
        <target>コンタクト情報の領域と例についてはISDIAH 5.2を参照してください。</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="36">
        <source>Description area</source>
        <target>記述のエリア</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="37">
        <source>"Record any relevant information about the history of the institution. This element may include information on dates of establishment, changes of names, changes of legislative mandates, or of any other sources of authority for the institution." (ISDIAH 5.3.1)</source>
        <target>"機関の歴史について関連情報を記載してください。この記述要素には、設立の日付、名称変更、設置法等、権限の根拠に加えられたあらゆる変更を含みます。" (ISDIAH 5.3.1)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="38">
        <source>"Identify the geographical area the institution belongs to. Record any other relevant information about the cultural context of the institution." (ISDIAH 5.3.2)</source>
        <target>組織の所在地を記入してください。組織の置かれた文化的情報に関し、関連情報があればそれも記載してください。 " (ISDIAH 5.3.2)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="39">
        <source>Geographical and cultural context</source>
        <target>地理的文化的コンテキスト</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="40">
        <source>"Record any document, law, directive or charter which acts as a source of authority for the powers, functions and responsibilities of the institution, together with information on the jurisdiction(s) and covering dates when the mandate(s) applied or were changed." (ISDIAH 5.3.3)</source>
        <target>"機関の権限、機能、責任の根拠となる文書、法律、命令、憲章等があれば全て記載してください。そうした法規等が適用となる地理的範囲、および施行日、改正日など時間的な範囲についての情報も添えて下さい。" (ISDIAH 5.3.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="41">
        <source>Mandates/Sources of authority</source>
        <target>要求（命令）/オーソリティの情報源</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="42">
        <source>"Describe, in narrative form or using organisational charts, the current administrative structure of the institution." (ISDIAH 5.3.4)</source>
        <target>"現在の組織構造を、文章あるいは組織図で記述してください。 (ISDIAH 5.3.4)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="43">
        <source>Administrative structure</source>
        <target>管理の構造</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="44">
        <source>"Record information about the records management and collecting policies of the institution. Define the scope and nature of material which the institution accessions. Indicate whether the repository seeks to acquire archival materials by transfer, gift, purchase and/or loan. If the policy includes active survey and/or rescue work, this might be spelt out." (ISDIAH 5.3.5)</source>
        <target>"機関におけるレコード・マネージメントと収集ポリシーについて記載してください。受け入れる資料の範囲と正確を明らかにしてください。また、移管、寄贈、購入、貸与等いずれの形式で受け入れるのかも示してください。収集ポリシーに、資料の所在調査や資料保存活動などが含まれるのであれば、それも記入してもかまいません。" (ISDIAH 5.3.5)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="45">
        <source>Records management and collecting policies</source>
        <target>記録管理と収集方針</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="46">
        <source>"Record information on the building(s) of the institution (general and architectural characteristics of the building, capacity of storage areas, etc). Where possible, provide information which can be used for generating statistics." (ISDIAH 5.3.6)</source>
        <target>"機関の建物（複数可）についての情報を記入してください（建物の一般的、あるいは建築上の特徴、収蔵量など）。可能であれば、統計の作成に利用可能な情報を提供してください。" (ISDIAH 5.3.6)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="47">
        <source>"Record a short description of the holdings of the institution, describing how and when they were formed. Provide information on volume of holdings, media formats, thematic coverage, etc." (ISDIAH 5.3.7)</source>
        <target>"機関の所蔵資料につき、それがいつ、どのように形成されたかも含めて簡潔に記述してください。所蔵する資料の量、媒体、主題などについても情報を記載してください。" (ISDIAH 5.3.7)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="48">
        <source>Archival and other holdings</source>
        <target>アーカイブズ資料及び他の所蔵資料</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="49">
        <source>"Record the title and other pertinent details of the published and/or unpublished finding aids and guides prepared by the institution and of any other relevant publications. Use ISO 690 Information and documentation – Bibliographic references and other national or international cataloguing rules." (ISDIAH 5.3.8)</source>
        <target>"機関によって出版された、あるいは未出版の検索手段やガイドのタイトルその他の情報、あるいは他に関連の出版物があればそれに関する情報を記載してください。 その際、ISO 690 Information and documentation：Bibliographic references その他の、国内的・国際的目録記述の標準を用いるようにしてください。" (ISDIAH 5.3.8)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="50">
        <source>Finding aids, guides and publications</source>
        <target>検索手段、ガイド、出版物</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="51">
        <source>Access area</source>
        <target>アクセス　エリア</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="52">
        <source>"Record the opening hours of the institution and annual, seasonal and public holidays, and any other planned closures. Record times associated with the availability and/or delivery of services (for example, exhibition spaces, reference services, etc.)." (ISDIAH 5.4.1)</source>
        <target>"機関の開館時間、年間・季節・公的な休日などの閉館予定日を記入してください。 サービスの提供が受けられるか否かに関わる時間等も記載してください。 (例えば展示スペース、レファレンス・サービスなどに関して)." (ISDIAH 5.4.1)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="53">
        <source>"Describe access policies, including any restrictions and/or regulations for the use of materials and facilities. Record information about registration, appointments, readers’ tickets, letters of introduction, admission fees, etc. Where appropriate, make reference to the relevant legislation." (ISDIAH 5.4.2)</source>
        <target>"資料の利用、あるいは施設に利用に関わる制限や規則を含む、アクセス・ポリシーを記述してください。利用者登録、事前予約、利用者証、紹介状、入館料などの情報を入力してください。必要に応じ、関連法規にも言及してください。" (ISDIAH 5.4.2)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="54">
        <source>Conditions and requirements</source>
        <target>アクセス状態と必要条件</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="55">
        <source>"Record information about travelling to the institution and details for users with disabilities, including building features, specialised equipment or tools, parking or lifts." (ISDIAH 5.4.3)</source>
        <target>"機関への交通・アクセスと、障害のある利用者のための情報、例えば建物の状況、障害者向けの設備や機器、駐車場やエレベーターの有無などを記載してください。" (ISDIAH 5.4.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="56">
        <source>Accessibility</source>
        <target>アクセシビリティ</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="57">
        <source>Services area</source>
        <target>サービスのエリア</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="58">
        <source>"Record information about the onsite services provided by the institution such as languages spoken by staff, research and consultation rooms, enquiry services, internal libraries, map, microfiches, audio-visual, computer rooms, etc. Record as well any relevant information about research services, such as research undertaken by the institution, and the fee charge if applicable." (ISDIAH 5.5.1)</source>
        <target>"機関を利用する際に提供されるサービスに関する情報を記載してください。例えばスタッフが話せる言語、調査・相談室、調査サービス、参考文献室、地図、マイクロフィッシュ、AV資料、コンピュータ室の有無などです。機関が利用者のための調査を行うかどうかや、その際の費用についても情報があれば記載してください。" (ISDIAH 5.5.1)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="59">
        <source>"Record information about reproduction services available to the public (microfilms, photocopies, photographs, digitised copies). Specify general conditions and restrictions to the services, including applicable fees and publication rules." (ISDIAH 5.5.2)</source>
        <target>"一般に利用可能な複製サービスに関する情報を記載してください（マイクロフィルム、コピー、写真撮影、デジタル複製）。複製サービスの条件や制限について、料金や出版に関する規則なども含め明記してください。 " (ISDIAH 5.5.2)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="60">
        <source>"Record information about spaces available for public use (permanent or temporary exhibitions, free or charged internet connection, cash machines, cafeterias, restaurants, shops, etc.)." (ISDIAH 5.5.3)</source>
        <target>公共利用スペースに関する情報を記載してください (常設・企画展示、無料・有料のインターネット接続、ATM、カフェテリア、レストラン、売店など)。" (ISDIAH 5.5.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="61">
        <source>Public areas</source>
        <target>公共のエリア</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="62">
        <source>Control area</source>
        <target>管理のエリア</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="63">
        <source>"Record a unique description identifier in accordance with local and/or national conventions. If the description is to be used internationally, record the code of the country in which the description was created in accordance with the latest version of ISO 3166 - Codes for the representation of names of countries. Where the creator of the description is an international organisation, give the organisational identifier in place of the country code." (ISIAH 5.6.1)</source>
        <target>"ローカルな、あるいは国レベルの規則に従い、記述ID（固有の値）を記載してください。記述が国際的に使用される可能性がある場合は、記述が作成された国の国名コードを、ISO3166の最新版に従って記入してください。記述作成者が国際機関である場合、国名コードの代わりに機関IDを記載してください。" (ISIAH 5.6.1)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="64">
        <source>Description identifier</source>
        <target>記述の識別子</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="65">
        <source>"Record the full authorised form of name(s) of the agency(ies) responsible for creating, modifying or disseminating the description or, alternatively, record a code for the agency in accordance with the national or international agency code standard." (ISDIAH 5.6.2)</source>
        <target>"記述の作成・訂正・発信について責任を負う機関の正式名称、あるいは国内・国際規則に従い付与された公認されたコードを記入してください。" (ISDIAH 5.6.2)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="66">
        <source>Institution identifier</source>
        <target>機関識別子</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="67">
        <source>"Record the names, and, where useful, the editions or publication dates of the conventions or rules applied. Specify, separately, which rules have been applied for creating the Authorised form(s) of name. Include reference to any system(s) of dating used to identify dates in this description (e.g. ISO 8601)." (ISDIAH 5.6.3)</source>
        <target>"使用した規則等の名称、また、必要に応じて規則の版や発行日付などの情報を記載してください。この記述要素とはべつに、公認の名称を作成するのに用いた規則等を明記してください。記述に用いた日付のシステムも表示してください（例：ISO8601)" (ISDIAH 5.6.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="68">
        <source>Rules and/or conventions used</source>
        <target>ルールおよび使用した規則</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="69">
        <source>The purpose of this field is "[t]o indicate the drafting status of the description so that users can understand the current status of the description." (ISDIAH 5.6.4). Select Final, Revised or Draft from the drop-down menu.</source>
        <target>このフィールドの目的は"ユーザーが現在の記述のステータスを理解できるように記述の当初のステータスを表示することである。" (ISDIAH 5.6.4)。 ドロップダウンメニューから、最終、改定、当初を選択する。</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="70">
        <source>Select Full, Partial or Minimal from the drop-down menu. "In the absence of national guidelines or rules, minimal descriptions are those that consist only of the three essential elements of an ISIAH compliant description (see 4.7), while full records are those that convey information for all relevant ISDIAH elements of description." (ISDIAH 5.6.5)</source>
        <target>ドロップダウンメニューから全部、一部、最低限を選択してください。”もし国内の基準やルールが無ければ、最低限の記述はISDIAHの3つの絶対不可欠な要素だけで構成され（4.7を見よ）全部記述はISDIAHの全ての記述要素と関連する情報を転用する."（ISDIAH5.6.5）</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="71">
        <source>"Record the date the description was created and the dates of any revisions to the description." (ISDIAH 5.6.6)</source>
        <target>"記述作成日、および訂正日を記入してください。" (ISDIAH 5.6.6)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="72">
        <source>Dates of creation, revision and deletion</source>
        <target>作成　訂正　削除の日付</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="73">
        <source>Select the language(s) of this record from the drop-down menu; enter the first few letters to narrow the choices. (ISDIAH 5.6.7)</source>
        <target>ドロップダウンメニューからこの記録の言語を選択してください。：選択を狭めるために冒頭の数文字を入力してください。(ISDIAH 5.6.7)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="74">
        <source>Select the script(s) of this record from the drop-down menu; enter the first few letters to narrow the choices. (ISDIAH 5.6.7)</source>
        <target>ドロップダウンメニューから典拠レコードのスクリプトを選択してください。：選択を狭めるために冒頭の数文字を入力してください。(</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="75">
        <source>"Record the sources consulted in establishing the description of the institution." (ISDIAH 5.6.8)</source>
        <target>"機関の記述にあたり参照した文献等を記載してください。" (ISDIAH 5.6.8)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="76">
        <source>Sources</source>
        <target>情報源</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="77">
        <source>"Record notes pertinent to the creation and maintenance of the description." (ISDIAH 5.6.9)</source>
        <target>"記述の作成とメンテナンスに関連する情報を記入してください。" (ISDIAH 5.6.9)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="79">
        <source>Cancel</source>
        <target>キャンセル</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="80">
        <source>Save</source>
        <target>保存</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="81">
        <source>Create</source>
        <target>作成する</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="84">
        <source>Parallel form(s) of name</source>
        <target>名称の異なる表記</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="85">
        <source>Other form(s) of name</source>
        <target>他の名称のフォーム</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="86">
        <source>Type</source>
        <target>種別</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="88">
        <source>History</source>
        <target>歴史</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="89">
        <source>Buildings</source>
        <target>構築</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="90">
        <source>Holdings</source>
        <target>所蔵</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="91">
        <source>Opening times</source>
        <target>開始時間</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="92">
        <source>Access conditions and requirements</source>
        <target>アクセス条件と要件</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="93">
        <source>Research services</source>
        <target>調査活動</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="94">
        <source>Reproduction services</source>
        <target>複製業務</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="95">
        <source>Status</source>
        <target>ステータス</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="96">
        <source>Level of detail</source>
        <target>詳細レベル</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="97">
        <source>Language(s)</source>
        <target>言語</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="98">
        <source>Script(s)</source>
        <target>スクリプト</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="99">
        <source>Maintenance notes</source>
        <target>メンテナンス注記</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="100">
        <source>Edit</source>
        <target>編集する</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="101">
        <source>Delete</source>
        <target>削除</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="102">
        <source>Add new</source>
        <target>新規追加</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="104">
        <source>Edit identity area</source>
        <target>アイデンティティのエリアを編集する</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="105">
        <source>Edit contact area</source>
        <target>連絡のエリアを編集する</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="106">
        <source>Edit description area</source>
        <target>記述のエリアを編集する</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="107">
        <source>Edit access area</source>
        <target>アクセスエリアを編集する</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="108">
        <source>Edit services area</source>
        <target>サービスのエリアを編集する</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="109">
        <source>Edit control area</source>
        <target>コントロールのエリアを編集する</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="111">
        <source>Primary contact</source>
        <target>はじめての連絡先</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="112">
        <source>Website</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="113">
        <source>Email</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="114">
        <source>Edit theme</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="115">
        <source>Last updated</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="116">
        <source>Access points</source>
        <target>アクセスポイント</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="117">
        <source>Edit access points</source>
        <target>アクセスポイントを編集する</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="118">
        <source>Access Points</source>
        <target>アクセスポイント</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="119">
        <source>Thematic area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="120">
        <source>Search for an existing term in the Thematic Areas taxonomy by typing the first few characters of the term name. This should be used to identify major collecting areas.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="121">
        <source>Geographic subregion</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="122">
        <source>Search for an existing term in the Geographic Subregion taxonomy by typing the first few characters of the term name.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="123">
        <source>Enter the digital latitude of the institution's physical location (rather than degrees, minutes and seconds), e.g. 49.459044</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="124">
        <source>Enter the digital longitude of the institution's physical location (rather than degrees, minutes and seconds), e.g. -104.296984</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="125">
        <source>Clipboard</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="126">
        <source>Add description</source>
        <target>記述を追加する</target>
      </trans-unit>
    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>
