<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE xliff PUBLIC "-//XLIFF//DTD XLIFF//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/committees/xliff/documents/xliff.dtd">
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file source-language="en" target-language="ru" datatype="plaintext" original="messages" date="2017-08-25T18:50:37Z" product-name="messages">
    <header/>
    <body>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Untitled</source>
        <target>Без названия</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="2">
        <source>Administrative history / Biographical sketch</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="3">
        <source>Administrative history</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="4">
        <source>Biographical sketch</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="5">
        <source>This archival description requires at least one date.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="6">
        <source>Date(s) - are not consistent with %1%higher levels%2%.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="7">
        <source>Physical description - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="8">
        <source>Title - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target>Название -Это обязательный элемент.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="9">
        <source>Level of description - Value "%value%" is not consistent with higher levels.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="10">
        <source>Level of description - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="11">
        <source>Statement of scale (architectural) - This is a mandatory element for architectural drawing.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="12">
        <source>Statement of coordinates (cartographic) - This is a mandatory element for cartographic material.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="13">
        <source>Statement of projection (cartographic) - This is a mandatory element for cartographic material.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="14">
        <source>Statement of scale (cartographic) - This is a mandatory element for cartographic material.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="15">
        <source>Issuing jurisdiction and denomination (philatelic) - This is a mandatory element for philatelic record.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="16">
        <source>Scope and content - This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="17">
        <source>Edition statement - This is a mandatory element for published items if there are multiple editions.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="18">
        <source>Add new archival description</source>
        <target>Добавить новое архивное описание</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="19">
        <source>Edit %1%</source>
        <target>Изменить %1%</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="20">
        <source>"Give the date(s) of creation of the unit being described either as a single date, or range of dates (for inclusive dates and/or predominant dates). Always give the inclusive dates. When providing predominant dates, specify them as such, preceded by the word predominant..." (RAD 1.4B2) Record probable and uncertain dates in square brackets, using the conventions described in 1.4B5.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="21">
        <source>"Make notes on dates and any details pertaining to the dates of creation, publication, or distribution, of the unit being described that are not included in the Date(s) of creation, including publication, distribution, etc., area and that are considered to be important." (RAD 1.8B8) "Make notes on the date(s) of accumulation or collection of the unit being described." (RAD 1.8B8a)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="22">
        <source>Select the type of activity that established the relation between the authority record and the archival description (e.g. creation, accumulation, collection, publication, etc.)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="23">
        <source>This is a duplicate of record %1%</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="24">
        <source>Title and statement of responsibility area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="25">
        <source>Enter the title proper, either transcribed or supplied. (RAD 1.1B)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="26">
        <source>Title proper</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="27">
        <source>This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target>Это обязательный элемент.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="28">
        <source>Select the General Material Designation at the highest level of description. If there are more than three, select "multiple media" (RAD 1.1C)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="29">
        <source>General material designation</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="30">
        <source>"[W]hen applicable, transcribe parallel titles that appear in conjunction with the formal title proper..." (RAD 1.1D)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="31">
        <source>Parallel titles</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="32">
        <source>"Transcribe other title information that appears in conjunction with the formal title proper..." (RAD 1.1E)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="33">
        <source>Other title information</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="34">
        <source>"At the item level of description, transcribe explicit statements of responsibility appearing in conjunction with the formal title proper in or on the chief source of information..." (RAD 1.1F)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="35">
        <source>Statement of responsibility</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="36">
        <source>Select a level of description from the drop-down menu. See RAD 1.0A for rules and conventions on selecting levels of description.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="37">
        <source>Level of description</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="38">
        <source>Identifier: Enter an unambiguous code used to uniquely identify the description. Level: Select a level of description from the drop-down menu. See RAD 1.0A for rules and conventions on selecting levels of description. Title: Enter the title proper, either transcribed or supplied. (RAD 1.1B)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="39">
        <source>Select the repository that has custody and control of the archival material. The values in this field are drawn from the Authorized form of name field in archival institution records. Search for an existing name by typing the first few characters of the name. Alternatively, type a new name to create and link to a new archival institution.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="40">
        <source>Enter an unambiguous code used to uniquely identify the description.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="41">
        <source>Reference code</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="42">
        <source>Edition area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="43">
        <source>"Use this area only in item level description to record statements relating to versions of items existing in two or more versions or states in single or multiple copies." (RAD 1.2A1) "Transcribe the edition statement relating to the item being described." (RAD 1.2B1) "If the item being described lacks an edition statement but is known to contain significant changes from other editions, supply a suitable brief statement in the language and script of the title proper and enclose it in square brackets." (RAD 1.2B3)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="44">
        <source>Edition statement</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="45">
        <source>"Transcribe a statement of responsibility relating to one or more editions, but not to all editions, of the item being described following the edition statement if there is one." (RAD 1.2.C1) "When describing the first edition, give all statements of responsibility in the Title and statement of responsibility area." (RAD 1.2C2)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="46">
        <source>Statement of responsibility relating to the edition</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="47">
        <source>Class of material specific details area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="48">
        <source>"Give the scale of the unit being described...as a representative fraction (RF) expressed as a ratio (1: ). Precede the ratio by Scale. Give the scale even if it is already recorded as part of the title proper or other title information." (RAD 5.3B1)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="49">
        <source>Statement of scale (cartographic)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="50">
        <source>"Give the statement of projection if it is found on the prescribed source(s) of information." (RAD 5.3C1)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="51">
        <source>Statement of projection (cartographic)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="52">
        <source>"At the fonds, series or file levels, record coordinates for the maximum coverage provided by the materials in the unit, as long as they are reasonably contiguous." (RAD 5.3D)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="53">
        <source>Statement of coordinates (cartographic)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="54">
        <source>"Give in English the scale in the units of measure found on the unit being described. If there is no English equivalent for the name of the unit of measure, give the name, within quotation marks, as found on the unit being described." (RAD 6.3B)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="55">
        <source>Statement of scale (architectural)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="56">
        <source>"Give the name of the jurisdiction (e.g., government) responsible for issuing the philatelic records." (RAD 12.3B1) "For all units possessing a denomination (e.g., postage stamps, revenue stamps, postal stationery items), give the denomination in a standardized format, recording the denomination number in arabic numerals followed by the name of the currency unit. Include a denomination statement even if the denomination is already recorded as part of the title proper or other title information." (RAD 12.3C1)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="57">
        <source>Issuing jurisdiction and denomination (philatelic)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="58">
        <source>Dates of creation area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="59">
        <source>Add new name and/or date(s)</source>
        <target>Добавить новое имя и/или дату(ы)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="60">
        <source>Physical description area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="61">
        <source>"At all levels record the extent of the unit being described by giving the number of physical units in arabic numerals and the specific material designation as instructed in subrule .5B in the chapter(s) dealing with the broad class(es) of material to which the unit being described belongs." (RAD 1.5B1) Include other physical details and dimensions as specified in RAD 1.5C and 1.5D. Separate multiple entries in this field with a carriage return (i.e. press the Enter key on your keyboard).</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="62">
        <source>Physical description</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="63">
        <source>Publisher's series area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="64">
        <source>"At the item level of description, transcribe a title proper of the publisher's series as instructed in 1.1B1." (RAD 1.6B)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="65">
        <source>Title proper of publisher's series</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="66">
        <source>"Transcribe parallel titles of a publisher's series as instructed in 1.1D." (RAD 1.6C1)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="67">
        <source>Parallel title of publisher's series</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="68">
        <source>"Transcribe other title information of a publisher's series as instructed in 1.1E and only if considered necessary for identifying the publisher's series." (RAD 1.6D1)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="69">
        <source>Other title information of publisher's series</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="70">
        <source>"Transcribe explicit statements of responsibility appearing in conjunction with a formal title proper of a publisher's series as instructed in 1.1F and only if considered necessary for identifying the publisher's series." (RAD 1.6E1)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="71">
        <source>Statement of responsibility relating to publisher's series</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="72">
        <source>"Give the numbering of the item within a publisher's series in the terms given in the item." (RAD 1.6F1)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="73">
        <source>Numbering within publisher's series</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="74">
        <source>"Make notes on important details of publisher's series that are not included in the Publisher's series area, including variant series titles, incomplete series, and of numbers or letters that imply a series." (RAD 1.8B10)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="75">
        <source>Note on publisher's series</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="76">
        <source>Archival description area</source>
        <target>Область архивного описания</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="77">
        <source>Edit authority record</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="78">
        <source>"Give the history of the custody of the unit being described, i.e., the successive transfers of ownership and custody or control of the material, along with the dates thereof, insofar as it can be ascertained." (RAD 1.7C)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="79">
        <source>Custodial history</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="80">
        <source>"At the fonds, series, and collection levels of description, and when necessary at the file and the item levels of description, indicate the level being described and give information about the scope and the internal structure of or arrangement of the records, and about their contents." (RAD 1.7D) "For the scope of the unit being described, give information about the functions and/or kinds of activities generating the records, the period of time, the subject matter, and the geographical area to which they pertain. For the content of the unit being described, give information about its internal structure by indicating its arrangement, organization, and/or enumerating its next lowest level of description. Summarize the principal documentary forms (e.g., reports, minutes, correspondence, drawings, speeches)." (RAD 1.7D1)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="81">
        <source>Scope and content</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="82">
        <source>Notes area</source>
        <target>Область заметок</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="83">
        <source>"Make notes on the physical condition of the unit being described if that condition materially affects the clarity or legibility of the records." (RAD 1.8B9a)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="84">
        <source>Physical condition</source>
        <target>Физическое состояние</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="85">
        <source>"Record the donor or source (i.e., the immediate prior custodian) from whom the unit being described was acquired, and the date and method of acquisition, as well as the source/donor's relationship to the material, if any or all of this information is not confidential. If the source/donor is unknown, record that information." (RAD 1.8B12)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="86">
        <source>Immediate source of acquisition</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="87">
        <source>"Make notes on the arrangement of the unit being described which contribute significantly to its understanding but cannot be put in the Scope and content (see 1.7D), e.g., about reorganisation(s) by the creator, arrangement by the archivist, changes in the classification scheme, or reconstitution of original order." (RAD 1.8B13)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="88">
        <source>"Record the language or languages of the unit being described, unless they are noted elsewhere or are apparent from other elements of the description." (RAD 1.8.B14). Select the language from the drop-down menu; enter the first few letters to narrow the choices.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="89">
        <source>Language of material</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="90">
        <source>"Note any distinctive alphabets or symbol systems employed." (RAD 1.8.B14) Select the script from the drop-down menu; enter the first few letters to narrow the choices.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="91">
        <source>Script of material</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="92">
        <source>"Record the language or languages of the unit being described, unless they are noted elsewhere or are apparent from other elements of the description. Also note any distinctive alphabets or symbol systems employed." (RAD 1.8B14). Do not duplicate information added via the drop-down in the language or script fields.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="93">
        <source>Language and script notes</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="94">
        <source>"If the unit being described is a reproduction and the location of the original material is known, give that location. Give, in addition, any identifying numbers that may help in locating the original material in the cited location. If the originals are known to be no longer extant, give that information." (RAD 1.8B15a)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="95">
        <source>"If all or part of the unit being described is available (either in the institution or elsewhere) in another format(s), e.g., if the text being described is also available on microfilm; or if a film is also available on videocassette, make a note indicating the other format(s) in which the unit being described is available and its location, if that information is known. If only a part of the unit being described is available in another format(s), indicate which parts." (RAD 1.8B15b)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="96">
        <source>Availability of other formats</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="97">
        <source>"Give information about any restrictions placed on access to the unit (or parts of the unit) being described." (RAD 1.8B16a)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="98">
        <source>Restrictions on access</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="99">
        <source>For terms governing use and reproduction, "Give information on legal or donor restrictions that may affect use or reproduction of the material." (RAD 1.8B16c). For terms governing publication, "Give information on legal or donor restrictions that may affect publication of the material." (RAD 1.8B16d)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="100">
        <source>Terms governing use, reproduction, and publication</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="101">
        <source>"Give information regarding the existence of any finding aids. Include appropriate administrative and/or intellectual control tools over the material in existence at the time the unit is described, such as card catalogues, box lists, series lists, inventories, indexes, etc." (RAD 1.8B17)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="102">
        <source>For associated material, "If records in another institution are associated with the unit being described by virtue of the fact that they share the same provenance, make a citation to the associated material at the fonds, series or collection level, or for discrete items, indicating its location if known." (RAD 1.8B18). For related material, "Indicate groups of records having some significant relationship by reason of shared responsibility or shared sphere of activity in one or more units of material external to the unit being described." (RAD 1.8B20)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="103">
        <source>Associated materials</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="104">
        <source>Related materials</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="105">
        <source>To create a relationship between this description and another description held in AtoM, begin typing the name of the related description and select it from the autocomplete drop-down menu when it appears below. Multiple relationships can be created.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="106">
        <source>"When the unit being described is not yet complete, e.g., an open fonds or series, make a note explaining that further accruals are expected... If no further accruals are expected, indicate that the unit is considered closed." (RAD 1.8B19)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="107">
        <source>Standard number area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="108">
        <source>"Give the International Standard Book Number (ISBN), International Standard Serial Number (ISSN), or any other internationally agreed standard number for the item being described. Give such numbers with the agreed abbreviation and with the standard spacing or hyphenation." (RAD 1.9B1)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="109">
        <source>Access points</source>
        <target>Точки доступа</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="110">
        <source>Subject access points</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="111">
        <source>Search for an existing term in the Subjects taxonomy by typing the first few characters of the term. Alternatively, type a new term to create and link to a new subject term.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="112">
        <source>Place access points</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="113">
        <source>Search for an existing term in the Places taxonomy by typing the first few characters of the term name. Alternatively, type a new term to create and link to a new place term.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="114">
        <source>Genre access points</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="115">
        <source>Search for an existing term in the Genre taxonomy by typing the first few characters of the term name. Alternatively, type a new term to create and link to a new genre term.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="116">
        <source>Name access points (subjects)</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="117">
        <source>"Choose provenance, author and other non-subject access points from the archival description, as appropriate. All access points must be apparent from the archival description to which they relate." (RAD 21.0B) The values in this field are drawn from the Authorized form of name field in authority records. Search for an existing name by typing the first few characters of the name. Alternatively, type a new name to create and link to a new authority record.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="118">
        <source>Control area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="119">
        <source>Record a unique description identifier in accordance with local and/or national conventions. If the description is to be used internationally, record the code of the country in which the description was created in accordance with the latest version of ISO 3166 - Codes for the representation of names of countries. Where the creator of the description is an international organisation, give the organisational identifier in place of the country code.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="120">
        <source>Description identifier</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="121">
        <source>Record the full authorised form of name(s) of the agency(ies) responsible for creating, modifying or disseminating the description or, alternatively, record a code for the agency in accordance with the national or international agency code standard.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="122">
        <source>Institution identifier</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="123">
        <source>Record the international, national and/or local rules or conventions followed in preparing the description.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="124">
        <source>Rules or conventions</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="125">
        <source>Status</source>
        <target>Статус</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="126">
        <source>Record the current status of the description, indicating whether it is a draft, finalized and/or revised or deleted.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="127">
        <source>Record whether the description consists of a minimal, partial or full level of detail in accordance with relevant international and/or national guidelines and/or rules.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="128">
        <source>Level of detail</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="129">
        <source>Record the date(s) the entry was prepared and/or revised.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="130">
        <source>Dates of creation, revision and deletion</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="131">
        <source>Indicate the language(s) used to create the description of the archival material.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="132">
        <source>Language</source>
        <target>Язык</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="133">
        <source>Indicate the script(s) used to create the description of the archival material.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="134">
        <source>Script</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="135">
        <source>Record citations for any external sources used in the archival description (such as the Scope and Content, Custodial History, or Notes fields).</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="136">
        <source>Sources</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="137">
        <source>Edit title and statement of responsibility area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="138">
        <source>Parallel title</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="139">
        <source>Title statements of responsibility</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="140">
        <source>Title notes</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="141">
        <source>Repository</source>
        <target>Хранилище</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="142">
        <source>Edit edition area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="143">
        <source>Edition statement of responsibility</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="144">
        <source>Edit class of material specific details area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="145">
        <source>Edit dates of creation area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="146">
        <source>Edit physical description area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="147">
        <source>Edit publisher's series area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="148">
        <source>Parallel titles of publisher's series</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="149">
        <source>Edit archival description area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="150">
        <source>Edit notes area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="151">
        <source>Arrangement</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="152">
        <source>Language and script note</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="153">
        <source>Location of originals</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="154">
        <source>Finding aids</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="155">
        <source>Accruals</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="156">
        <source>General note</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="157">
        <source>Edit standard number area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="158">
        <source>Standard number</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="159">
        <source>Edit access points</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="160">
        <source>Edit control area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="161">
        <source>Description record identifier</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="162">
        <source>Language of description</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="163">
        <source>Script of description</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="164">
        <source>Rights area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="165">
        <source>Accession area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>
