<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE xliff PUBLIC "-//XLIFF//DTD XLIFF//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/committees/xliff/documents/xliff.dtd">
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file source-language="EN" target-language="id" datatype="plaintext" original="messages" date="2017-08-25T18:50:43Z" product-name="messages">
    <header/>
    <body>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Add new resource</source>
        <target>Tambahkan sumber informasi lain</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="2">
        <source>Untitled</source>
        <target>tanpa judul</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="3">
        <source>Edit %1%</source>
        <target>Ubah %1%</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="4">
        <source>Select the type of activity that established the relation between the authority record and the resource.</source>
        <target>Pilih tipe aktivitas yang menjelaskan relasi antara pencipta arsip dan sumber arsip.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="7">
        <source>Identifier</source>
        <target>Kode unik</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="8">
        <source>Title</source>
        <target>Judul</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="9">
        <source>Type of resource</source>
        <target>Tipe dari sumber informasi</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="10">
        <source>Language</source>
        <target>Bahasa</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="11">
        <source>Internet media type</source>
        <target>Tipe media Internet</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="12">
        <source>Subject</source>
        <target>Subjek</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="13">
        <source>Access condition</source>
        <target>Kondisi Akses</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="14">
        <source>URL</source>
        <target>URL</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="15">
        <source>Physical location</source>
        <target>Lokasi Fisik</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="16">
        <source>Rights area</source>
        <target>Area Pemegang Hak</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="18">
        <source>Accession area</source>
        <target>Bagian akuisisi</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="20">
        <source>This is a duplicate of record %1%</source>
        <target>Ini adalah duplikasi dari arsip %1%</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="21">
        <source>Contains a unique standard number or code that distinctively identifies a resource.</source>
        <target>Cantumkan standar nomor unik atau kode yang secara jelas mengidentifikasikan sumber informasi arsip.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="22">
        <source>A word, phrase, character, or group of characters, normally appearing in a resource, that names it or the work contained in it. Choice and format of titles should be governed by a content standard such as the Anglo-American Cataloging Rules, 2nd edition (AACR2), Cataloguing Cultural Objects (CCO), or Describing Archives: A Content Standard (DACS). Details such as capitalization, choosing among the forms of titles presented on an item, and use of abbreviations should be determined based on the rules in a content standard. One standard should be chosen and used consistently for all records in a set.</source>
        <target>Kata, frase, huruf, kelompok huruf, umumnya tampak pada sumber informasi, pada nama atau kegiatan yang terdapat didalamnya. Pilihan dan format dari judul seharusnya ditentukan berdasarkan standar seperti the Anglo-American Cataloging Rules, 2nd edition (AACR2), Cataloguing Cultural Objects (CCO), or Describing Archives: A Content Standard (DACS). Detail seperti huruf kapital, pemilihan format jusul yang digunakan untuk item, dan penggunaan singkatan harus ditetapkan berdasarkan isi dari aturan yang ada dalam standar. Sebuah standar harus dipilih dan digunakan secara konsisten untuk semua arsip yang berada dalam suatu kumpulan berkas.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="23">
        <source>Names and origin info</source>
        <target>Nama dan info original</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="24">
        <source>Add new name and/or origin info</source>
        <target>Tambahkan nama dan/ atau informasi asli atau original</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="25">
        <source>A term that specifies the characteristics and general type of content of the resource. Assign as many types as are applicable. The Type of resource options are limited to the values in the MODS typeOfResource top-level element.</source>
        <target>Istilah yang menjelaskan karakteristik dan jenis dari sumber informasi arsip. Tentukan sesuai kebutuhan sumber informasi arsip sebagaimana tersedia. Jenis berkas dibatasi oleh nilai dari elemen level teratas MODS typeOfResource.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="26">
        <source>Add new child levels (if describing a collection)</source>
        <target>Tambahkan Level setingkat dibawah (jika mendeskripsikan koleksi arsip)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="27">
        <source>Use these two fields to add lower levels to a collection-level description. Click Add new to add as many child levels as necessary. Identifer: enter a unique standard number or code that distinctively identifies the resource. Title: enter A word, phrase, character, or group of characters, normally appearing in a resource, that names it or the work contained in it.</source>
        <target>Gunakan dua field ini untuk menambahkan koleksi dengan level deskripsi yang lebih rendah. Klik Tambah utnuk menambahkan level yang lebih rendah dibawahnya sesuai keinginan. Identifier: berikan nomor standar yang unik atau kode yang secara istimewa membedakan sumber informasi arsip. Judul: berikan informasi berupa kata, frase, karakter, atau kumpulan karakter, yang tercantum pada sumber informasi arsip, yang ada atau merupakan bagian dari sumber informasi tersebut.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="28">
        <source>A designation of the language in which the content of a resource is expressed. Select as many languages as required.</source>
        <target>Tentukan bahasa yang digunakan dalam konten arsip. Pilih bahasa yang sesuai dengan berkas arsip.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="29">
        <source>A term or phrase representing the primary topic(s) on which a work is focused. Search for an existing term in the Subjects taxonomy by typing the first few characters of the term name. Alternatively, type a new name to create and link to a new subject term.</source>
        <target>Istilah atau frase yang mewakili topik utama berkas. Cari istilah yang sudah terdapat dalam daftar taksonomi subjek dengan mengetikkan beberapa karakter dari nama istilah. Atau, ketik nama baru dan hubungkan dengan istilah subjek baru.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="30">
        <source>Information about restrictions imposed on access to a resource. See MODS accessCondition top-level element for more information on how to use this field.</source>
        <target>Informasi mengenai batasan akses kepada sumber informasi arsip. Lihat MODS 'accessCondition top-level element' untuk informasi lebih lanjut mengenai bagaimana menggunakan bagian ini.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="31">
        <source>Identifies the institution or repository holding the resource. Search for an existing repository name by typing the first few letters of the name. ALternatively, type a new name to create and link to a new repository record.</source>
        <target>Indentifikasi institusi atau repositori yang menyimpan sumber informasi arsip. Cari untuk repositori yang sudah ada dengan ketik beberapa kata dari nama. Atau, ketik nama baru dan hubungkan dengan repositori baru yang menyimpan arsip tersebut.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="32">
        <source>Elements area</source>
        <target>Bagian elemen</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="37">
        <source>Edit elements area</source>
        <target>Ubah bagian elemen </target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="38">
        <source>Places</source>
        <target>Tempat</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="39">
        <source>Search for an existing term in the Places taxonomy by typing the first few characters of the term name. Alternatively, type a new term to create and link to a new place term.</source>
        <target>Cari nama tempat yang sudah ada pada daftar taksonomi dengan ketik beberapa huruf awal dari nama tempat. Atau, ketik istilah baru untuk menciptakan nama tempat yang sesuai.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="40">
        <source>Names</source>
        <target>Nama</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="41">
        <source>"Choose provenance, author and other non-subject access points from the archival description, as appropriate. All access points must be apparent from the archival description to which they relate." (RAD 21.0B) The values in this field are drawn from the Authorized form of name field in authority records. Search for an existing name by typing the first few characters of the name. Alternatively, type a new name to create and link to a new authority record.</source>
        <target>"Pilihlah provenance, pencipta, dan non-subjek lainnya yang digunakan sebagai akses poin dari arsip yang sedang dideskripsikan, setepat mungkin." (RAD 21.0B) Field ini merupakan penjelasan penanggung jawab dari authority record/ pencipta arsip. Cari untuk beberapa nama yang sudah ada dengan ketik beberapa kata, atau ketik nama baru untuk membuat dan menghubungkan dengan pencipta arsip yang baru.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="42">
        <source>An abstract, table of contents or description of the resource's scope and contents.</source>
        <target>Abstrak, daftar isi atau deskripsi dari cakupan dan isi sumber informasi arsip.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="43">
        <source>Description</source>
        <target>Deskripsi</target>
      </trans-unit>
    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>
