<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE xliff PUBLIC "-//XLIFF//DTD XLIFF//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/committees/xliff/documents/xliff.dtd">
<xliff version="1.0">
  <file source-language="EN" target-language="ko" datatype="plaintext" original="messages" date="2017-09-04T11:51:15Z" product-name="messages">
    <header/>
    <body>
      <trans-unit id="1">
        <source>Add new authority record</source>
        <target>새로운 전거레코드 추가</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="2">
        <source>Untitled</source>
        <target>제목없음</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="3">
        <source>Edit %1%</source>
        <target>%1% 편집</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="4">
        <source>%1%Authorized form of name%2% - This is a %3%mandatory%4% element.</source>
        <target>%1%이름의 전거형-Authorized form of name %2% - 이것은 %3%필수%4% 요소이다.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="5">
        <source>%1%Dates of existence%2% - This is a %3%mandatory%4% element.</source>
        <target>%1%실존 기간%2% - 이 항목은 %3%필수%4% 요소입니다.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="7">
        <source>%1%Type of entity%2% - This is a %3%mandatory%4% element.</source>
        <target>%1%객체 유형%2% - 이 항목은 %3%필수%4% 요소입니다.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="8">
        <source>Related resources</source>
        <target>관련 소스</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="9">
        <source>Title</source>
        <target>제목</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="10">
        <source>Relationship</source>
        <target>관계</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="11">
        <source>Dates</source>
        <target>시기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="12">
        <source>Title of related resource</source>
        <target>관련자료 제목</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="13">
        <source>"Provide the unique identifiers/reference codes and/or titles for the related resources." (ISAAR 6.1) Select the title from the drop-down menu; enter the identifier or the first few letters to narrow the choices.</source>
        <target>"관련된 자원의 식별자/참조코드 또는 제목을 제공한다. (ISAAR 6.1)" 드롭다운 메뉴에서 제목을 선택하시오. 식별자 또는 처음 몇 글자를 기입하여 선택을 줄이시오.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="14">
        <source>"Describe the nature of the relationships between the corporate body, person or family and the related resource." (ISAAR 6.3) Select the type of relationship from the drop-down menu; these values are drawn from the Event Types taxonomy.</source>
        <target>"단체, 개인, 가문과 관련된 자원과의 관계의 성격을 기술한다." (ISAAR 6.3) 드롭다운메뉴에서 관계 타입을 선택하시오. 이 값은 이벤트 타입 분류로부터 추출합니다.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="15">
        <source>Nature of relationship</source>
        <target>관계 성격</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="16">
        <source>"Identify the type of related resources, e.g. Archival materials (fonds, record series, etc), archival description, finding aid, monograph, journal article, web site, photograph, museum collection, documentary film, oral history recording." (ISAAR 6.2) In the current version of the software, Archival material is provided as the only default value.</source>
        <target>관련된 자원의 유형을 식별한다(예: 기록물(퐁, 레코드 시리즈 등), 기록물 기술, 검색도구, 전공논문, 학술논문, 웹사이트, 사진, 박물류, 다큐멘터리 필름, 구술기록). (ISAAR 6.2) 현 버젼의 소프트웨어에서 아카이브 자료는 오로지 디폴트 값만 제공됩니다.
</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="17">
        <source>Type of related resource</source>
        <target>관련자료 형태</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="18">
        <source>"Provide any relevant dates for the related resources and/or the relationship between the corporate body, person or family and the related resource." (ISAAR 6.4) Enter the date as you would like it to appear in the show page for the authority record, using qualifiers and/or typographical symbols to express uncertainty if desired.</source>
        <target>관련된 자원과 관련된 날짜나 단체, 개인, 가문과 관련된 자원 사이의 관계의 기간을 제공하고 그러한 날짜의 중요성을 제공한다. (ISAAR 6.4)
</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="19">
        <source>Related corporate bodies, persons or families</source>
        <target>관련 조직/기관, 개인, 가족 </target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="20">
        <source>Name</source>
        <target>이름</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="21">
        <source>Type</source>
        <target>형태</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="22">
        <source>Description</source>
        <target>기술</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="23">
        <source>Related corporate body, person or family</source>
        <target>관련 조직/기관, 개인, 가족</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="24">
        <source>Authorized form of name</source>
        <target>승인된 이름 형식</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="25">
        <source>"Record the authorized form of name and any relevant unique identifiers, including the authority record identifier, for the related entity." (ISAAR 5.3.1) Select the name from the drop-down menu; enter the first few letters to narrow the choices.</source>
        <target>관련된 개체의 전거표목과 전거레코드 식별자를 포함하여 적절하고 유일한 식별자를 기록하라. (ISAAR 5.3.1)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="26">
        <source>"Purpose: To identify the general category of relationship between the entity being described and another corporate body, person or family." (ISAAR 5.3.2). Select a category from the drop-down menu: hierarchical, temporal, family or associative.</source>
        <target>"목적: 기술되는 개체와 다른 단체, 개인 또는 가문간의 일반적인 관계의 종류를 확인한다." (ISAAR 5.3.2) 드롭다운 메뉴에서 계층적, 전후, 가족, 기타 관계 중 범주를 선택하라. 
</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="27">
        <source>Category of relationship</source>
        <target>관계 범주</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="28">
        <source>"Record a precise description of the nature of the relationship between the entity described in this authority record and the other related entity....Record in the Rules and/or conventions element (5.4.3) any classification scheme used as a source of controlled vocabulary terms to describe the relationship. A narrative description of the history and/or nature of the relationship may also be provided here." (ISAAR 5.3.3). Note that the text entered in this field will also appear in the related authority record.</source>
        <target>해당 전거레코드 내에서 기술되는 개체와 다른 관련된 개체간의 관계의 특성에 대한 명확한 기술을 기록한다. ... 관계를 기술하기 위해 사용된 통제된 어휘의 분류체계는 규칙과 협약 항목(5.4.3)에 기록해라. 관계의 연혁나 특성에 대한 서사적 기술도 여기에 제공된다. (ISAAR 5.3.3). 해당 항목에 기입되는 개체도 관련 전거레코드에 의해 드러나도록 기재하라.	</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="29">
        <source>Description of relationship</source>
        <target>관계 기술</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="30">
        <source>"Record when relevant the commencement date of the relationship or succession date and, when relevant, the cessation date of the relationship." (ISAAR 5.3.4) Enter the date as you would like it to appear in the show page for the authority record, using qualifiers and/or typographical symbols to express uncertainty if desired.</source>
        <target>관계 시작일자, 관계 지속기간 그리고 관계 종료날짜가 언제인지를 기록한다. (ISAAR 5.3.4)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="31">
        <source>Edit %1% - ISAAR</source>
        <target>편집 ISAAR</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="32">
        <source>Identity area</source>
        <target>식별 영역</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="33">
        <source>"Specify the type of entity that is being described in this authority record." (ISAAR 5.1.1) Select Corporate body, Family or Person from the drop-down menu.</source>
        <target>전거레코드에 기술되는 개체의 종류를 기입한다. (ISAAR 5.1.1)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="34">
        <source>Type of entity</source>
        <target>존재의 형태(조직/기관, 개인, 가족)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="35">
        <source>This is a mandatory element.</source>
        <target>이 항목은 필수 요소입니다.</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="36">
        <source>"Record the standardized form of name for the entity being described in accordance with any relevant national or international conventions or rules applied by the agency that created the authority record. Use dates, place, jurisdiction, occupation, epithet and other qualifiers as appropriate to distinguish the authorized form of name from those of other entities with similar names." (ISAAR 5.1.2)</source>
        <target>개체의 표준화된 명칭을 관련된 국가적 또는 국제적 협약이나 전거레코드를 생산한 기관이 적용한 규칙에 따라 기술한다. 비슷한 이름의 다른 개체와 표준화된 형태의 이름을 구분하기 위해 날짜, 장소, 관할지역, 직업, 별명 그리고 기타 적절한 한정어를 사용한다. (ISAAR 5.1.2)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="37">
        <source>"Purpose: To indicate the various forms in which the Authorized form of name occurs in other languages or script form(s). Rule: record the parallel form(s) of name in accordance with any relevant national or international conventions or rules applied by the agency that created the authority record, including any necessary sub elements and/or qualifiers required by those conventions or rules." (ISAAR 5.1.3)</source>
        <target>"목적: 공식 기능어를 다른 언어나 문자로 표현한 기능어를 기술하기 위한 요소     
규칙: 기술을 생산한 기관이 채택한 국가 혹은 국제 규약/규칙에 따라 대등기능어를 기록한다. 규약이나 규칙에 따라 필요한 모든 하위요소들과 한정어를 포함한다. 어떤 규칙이 적용되었는지 규칙/규약 요소(5,4,3)에서 지정한다." (ISAAR 5.1.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="38">
        <source>Parallel form(s) of name</source>
        <target>이름 병기 형식</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="39">
        <source>"Record the standardized form of name for the entity being described in accordance with other conventions or rules. Specify the rules and/or if appropriate the name of the agency by which these standardized forms of name have been constructed." (ISAAR 5.1.4)</source>
        <target>다른 규칙이나 협약에 따라 기술된 개체의 표준화된 표목 형태를 기입한다. 규칙을 기입하고 만약 적합하다면 전거표목을 구축한 기관의 이름을 써라. (ISAAR 5.1.4)	</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="40">
        <source>Standardized form(s) of name according to other rules</source>
        <target>다른 규칙에 따른 표목의 표준형태</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="41">
        <source>The purpose of this field is to "indicate any other name(s) for the corporate body, person or family not used elsewhere in the Identity Area." Examples are acronyms, previous names, pseudonyms, maiden names and titles of nobility or honour. (ISAAR 5.1.5)</source>
        <target>이 필드의 목적은 "식별영역의 다른 부분에서 기술되지 않은 단체, 개인, 가문의 다른 이름을 나타내는" 것이다. 예를 들어 두문자어, 이전에 썼던 이름, 필명, 결혼하기 전의 성(姓), 귀족칭호, 명예직위가 있다. (ISAAR 5.1.5)	</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="42">
        <source>Other form(s) of name</source>
        <target>다른 이름 형식</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="43">
        <source>"Record where possible any official number or other identifier (e.g. a company registration number) for the corporate body and reference the jurisdiction and scheme under which it has been allocated." (ISAAR 5.1.6)</source>
        <target>할당받은 단체의 공식적인 번호나 다른 식별자(예를 들어, 회사등록번호)를 기록하고, 관할권과 조직(scheme)에 대해서도 언급한다. (ISAAR 5.1.6)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="44">
        <source>Identifiers for corporate bodies</source>
        <target>조직/기관 식별자</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="45">
        <source>Description area</source>
        <target>기술 영역</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="46">
        <source>"Record the dates of existence of the entity being described. For corporate bodies include the date of establishment/foundation/enabling legislation and dissolution. For persons include the dates or approximate dates of birth and death or, when these dates are not known, floruit dates. Where parallel systems of dating are used, equivalences may be recorded according to relevant conventions or rules. Specify in the Rules and/or conventions element (5.4.3) the system(s) of dating used, e.g. ISO 8601." (ISAAR 5.2.1)</source>
        <target>기술되는 개체의 존속시간을 기입한다. 단체는 설립/창설/법률제정과 해산 날짜를 모두 포함한다. 개인의 경우에는 정확하거나 대략적인 생몰일자를 기입하고 모를 경우에는 활약기(floruit dates)를 포함한다. 유사한 날짜체계가 사용될 때는 관련협약이나 규칙에 따라 기록한다. 예를 들어, 규칙이나 협약 항목(5.4.3)에 ISO에서 사용하고 있는 날짜체계(ISO 8601)를 기입한다. (ISAAR 5.2.1)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="47">
        <source>Dates of existence</source>
        <target>존재 시기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="48">
        <source>"Record in narrative form or as a chronology the main life events, activities, achievements and/or roles of the entity being described. This may include information on gender, nationality, family and religious or political affiliations. Wherever possible, supply dates as an integral component of the narrative description." (ISAAR 5.2.2)</source>
        <target>기술되는 개체의 생애에서 주요 사건, 활동, 업적, 역할에 대해 서술형태나 연대기적 형태로 기록한다. 여기에는 성(性), 국적, 가문, 그리고 종교 또는 정치적 관계가 포함된다. 가능하다면 서술형 기술의 필수구성요소인 날짜를 제공하도록 한다. (ISAAR 5.2.2)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="49">
        <source>"Purpose: to indicate the predominant places and/or jurisdictions where the corporate body, person or family was based, lived or resided or had some other connection. Rule: record the name of the predominant place(s)/jurisdiction(s), together with the nature and covering dates of the relationship with the entity." (ISAAR 5.2.3)</source>
        <target>"목적: 단체, 개인, 가문이 기반을 두거나 살았거나 또는 거주하였거나 그 밖의 관계를 맺었던 주된 장소를 나타낸다. 규칙: 개체와 관계를 맺은 날짜와 관계의 특성(성격)과 함께 주요 장소/관할권의 이름을 기입한다." (ISAAR 5.2.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="50">
        <source>"Record the legal status and where appropriate the type of corporate body together with the covering dates when this status applied." (ISAAR 5.2.4)</source>
        <target>그러한 지위가 적용되었던 날짜와 함께 단체의 법적 지위와 적절한 유형을 기록한다. (ISAAR 5.2.4)	</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="51">
        <source>"Record the functions, occupations and activities performed by the entity being described, together with the covering dates when useful. If necessary, describe the nature of the function, occupation or activity." (ISAAR 5.2.5)</source>
        <target>기술되는 개체에 의해 수행된 기능, 업무 그리고 활동을 해당되는 날짜와 함께 기록한다. 필요한 경우, 기능, 업무 또는 활동의 성격에 대해서도 기술한다. (ISAAR 5.2.5)	</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="52">
        <source>Functions, occupations and activities</source>
        <target>기능, 직업, 활동</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="53">
        <source>"Record any document, law, directive or charter which acts as a source of authority for the powers, functions and responsibilities of the entity being described, together with information on the jurisdiction(s) and covering dates when the mandate(s) applied or were changed." (ISAAR 5.2.6)</source>
        <target>기술되는 개체의 권한, 기능, 책임에 대한 권한의 근거로 작용하는 문서, 법률, 지령 또는 설립허가서를 관할권과 권한이 적용되거나 바뀐 시간을 함께 포함하여 기록한다. (ISAAR 5.2.6)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="54">
        <source>Mandates/sources of authority</source>
        <target>권한/권한의 근거</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="55">
        <source>"Describe the internal structure of a corporate body and the dates of any changes to that structure that are significant to the understanding of the way that corporate body conducted its affairs (e.g. by means of dated organization charts). Describe the genealogy of a family (e.g. by means of a family tree) in a way that demonstrates the inter-relationships of its members with covering dates." (ISAAR 5.2.7)</source>
        <target>조직의 내부 구조와 조직이 업무를 수행하는 방식을 이해하는 데에 중요한 구조 변화 일자(예: 날짜가 기입된 조직도를 통해)를 기술하라. 가문 구성원들 간의 상호관계를 해당 기간과 함께 설명하는 방식으로 가문의 계보(예를 들어 가계도를 통해)를 기술하라. (ISAAR 5.2.7)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="56">
        <source>Internal structures/genealogy</source>
        <target>내부 조직/가계</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="57">
        <source>"Provide any significant information on the social, cultural, economic, political and/or historical context in which the entity being described operated." (ISAAR 5.2.8)</source>
        <target>"기술되는 개체의 사회, 문화, 경제, 정치 그리고 역사적 배경에 관한 중요 정보를 제시한다." (ISAAR 5.2.8)	
</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="58">
        <source>Relationships area</source>
        <target>관계 영역</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="59">
        <source>Control area</source>
        <target>제어 영역</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="60">
        <source>"Record a unique authority record identifier in accordance with local and/or national conventions. If the authority record is to be used internationally, record the country code of the country in which the authority record was created in accordance with the latest version of ISO 3166 Codes for the representation of names of countries. Where the creator of the authority record is an international organization, give the organizational identifier in place of the country code." (ISAAR 5.4.1)</source>
        <target>지역 또는 국가 협약에 따라 전거레코드 식별자를 기록한다. 만약 전거레코드가 국제적으로 이용될 경우에는 ISO 3166 국가명 표현을 위한 규약(Codes for the representation of names of countries)의 최신판에 따라 전거레코드를 생산한 국가의 국가코드를 기록한다. 전거레코드의 생산자가 국제적인 조직인 경우에는 국가코드 대신에 조직 식별자를 기록한다. (ISAAR 5.4.1)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="62">
        <source>"Record the full authorized form of name(s) of the agency(ies) responsible for creating, modifying or disseminating the authority record or, alternatively, record a code for the agency in accordance with the national or international agency code standard. Include reference to any systems of identification used to identify the institutions (e.g. ISO 15511)." (ISAAR 5.4.2)</source>
        <target>전거레코드의 생산, 수정, 배포에 책임을 지는 기관의 전거형태를 기록하거나 국가적 또는 국제적 기관코드표준에 따라 기관의 코드를 기록한다. 기관을 식별하기 위해 사용한 식별체계에 대한 언급도 포함한다.(예: ISO 15511) (ISAAR 5.4.2)	</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="63">
        <source>Institution identifier</source>
        <target>전거레코드 책임기관 식별자</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="64">
        <source>"Purpose: To identify the national or international conventions or rules applied in creating the archival authority record. Rule: Record the names and where useful the editions or publication dates of the conventions or rules applied. Specify separately which rules have been applied for creating the Authorized form of name. Include reference to any system(s) of dating used to identify dates in this authority record (e.g. ISO 8601)." (ISAAR 5.4.3)</source>
        <target>"목적: 기록물 전거레코드의 작성시 적용한 국가적 또는 국제적 규칙이나 협약을 확인한다. 규칙: 적용된 협약이나 규칙의 이름과 출판날짜 (보급)판을 기록한다. 전거표목의 작성시 적용된 규칙을 각각 적는다. 이러한 전거레코드의 날짜를 식별하기 위해 사용한 날짜체계에 대한 언급도 포함한다(예: ISO 8601)." (ISAAR 5.4.3)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="65">
        <source>Rules and/or conventions used</source>
        <target>규칙 및 협약</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="66">
        <source>The purpose of this field is "[t]o indicate the drafting status of the authority record so that users can understand the current status of the authority record." (ISAAR 5.4.4). Select Final, Revised or Draft from the drop-down menu.</source>
        <target>해당 항목의 목적은 "이용자가 전거레코드의 현재상태를 이해할 수 있도록 하기 위해 전거레코드의 초안상태를 나타내는 것"이다. (ISAAR 5.4.4)	</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="67">
        <source>Select Full, Partial or Minimal from the drop-down menu. "In the absence of national guidelines or rules, minimal records are those that consist only of the four essential elements of an ISAAR(CPF) compliant authority record (see 4.8), while full records are those that convey information for all relevant ISAAR(CPF) elements of description." (ISAAR 5.4.5)</source>
        <target>가이드라인이나 규칙이 없을 때는 최소한의 레코드는 ISAAR(CPF)의 네 가지 필수요소로 구성되고(4.8을 보라), 반면에 완전한 상태의 레코드는 모든 관련된 ISAAR(CPF)의 기술요소를 나타내야 한다. (ISAAR 5.4.5)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="68">
        <source>"Record the date the authority record was created and the dates of any revisions to the record." (ISAAR 5.4.6)</source>
        <target>전거레코드가 생산된 날짜와 레코드에 대한 수정일자를 기록하라. (ISAAR 5.4.6)	</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="69">
        <source>Dates of creation, revision and deletion</source>
        <target>생산 수정 삭제 일자</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="70">
        <source>Select the language(s) of the authority record from the drop-down menu; enter the first few letters to narrow the choices. (ISAAR 5.4.7)</source>
        <target>드롭다운 메뉴에서 전거레코드의 언어(들)을 선택하시오; 선택의 폭을 좁히기 위해 처음 몇개의 글자를 입력하시오. (ISAAR 5.4.7)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="71">
        <source>Select the script(s) of the authority record from the drop-down menu; enter the first few letters to narrow the choices. (ISAAR 5.4.7)</source>
        <target>드롭다운 메뉴에서 전거레코드의 규약(들)을 선택하시오; 선택의 폭을 좁히기 위해 처음 몇개의 글자를 입력하시오. (ISAAR 5.4.7)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="72">
        <source>"Record the sources consulted in establishing the authority record." (ISAAR 5.4.8)</source>
        <target>전거레코드를 만드는데 참고했던 정보원을 기록한다. (ISAAR 5.4.8)	</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="73">
        <source>"Record notes pertinent to the creation and maintenance of the authority record. The names of persons responsible for creating the authority record may be recorded here." (ISAAR 5.4.9)</source>
        <target>전거레코드의 생산, 유지와 관련이 있는 주기를 기록한다. 전거레코드의 생산에 책임을 지는 사람의 이름을 여기에 기록해라. (ISAAR 5.4.9)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="75">
        <source>Cancel</source>
        <target>취소</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="76">
        <source>Save</source>
        <target>저장</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="77">
        <source>Create</source>
        <target>생성하기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="80">
        <source>History</source>
        <target>조직사, 개인/가족이력</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="81">
        <source>Places</source>
        <target>장소</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="82">
        <source>Legal status</source>
        <target>조직/기관의 법적 지위</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="83">
        <source>General context</source>
        <target>일반 맥락</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="84">
        <source>Related entity</source>
        <target>관련 단체</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="85">
        <source>Identifier of the related entity</source>
        <target>관련된 엔티티의 식별자</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="86">
        <source>Category of the relationship</source>
        <target>관계 범주</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="87">
        <source>Dates of the relationship</source>
        <target>관계 일자</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="88">
        <source>Related function</source>
        <target>관련 기능</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="89">
        <source>Status</source>
        <target>전거레코드 현지위</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="90">
        <source>Level of detail</source>
        <target>전거레코드 상세정도</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="91">
        <source>Language(s)</source>
        <target>언어(들)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="92">
        <source>Script(s)</source>
        <target>규약(들)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="93">
        <source>Sources</source>
        <target>자료</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="94">
        <source>Maintenance notes</source>
        <target>유지 주기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="95">
        <source>Edit</source>
        <target>편집</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="96">
        <source>Delete</source>
        <target>삭제</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="97">
        <source>Add new</source>
        <target>새항목 추가</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="98">
        <source>Edit identity area</source>
        <target>식별 영역 편집</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="99">
        <source>Edit description area</source>
        <target>기술 영역 편집하기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="100">
        <source>Edit relationships area</source>
        <target>관계 영역 편집하기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="101">
        <source>Edit control area</source>
        <target>제어 영역 편집하기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="103">
        <source>Export</source>
        <target>내보내기</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="104">
        <source>EAC</source>
        <target>EAC</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="105">
        <source>Last updated</source>
        <target>최종 업데이트</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="106">
        <source>Category</source>
        <target>범주</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="107">
        <source>Relationship type</source>
        <target>관계 종류</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="108">
        <source>"Select a descriptive term from the drop-down menu to clarify the type of relationship between these two actors."</source>
        <target>"이 두 배우의 관계를 명확하게 하기 위해서 드롭다운 메뉴에서 기술 용어를 선택하세요."</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="109">
        <source>Type of relationship</source>
        <target>관계의 종류</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="110">
        <source>%1%Authority record identifier%2% - This is a %3%mandatory%4% element.</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="111">
        <source>Access points</source>
        <target>접근점</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="112">
        <source>Authority record identifier</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="113">
        <source>Maintaining repository</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="114">
        <source>Clipboard</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="115">
        <source>Access points area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="116">
        <source>Edit access points area</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="117">
        <source>Occupations</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="118">
        <source>Note</source>
        <target>주기(노트)</target>
      </trans-unit>
      <trans-unit id="119">
        <source>Maintained by</source>
        <target/>
      </trans-unit>
    </body>
  </file>
</xliff>
